Gaming.
On a Sunday.
I'm back home.
Oh, man.
I'm ready, man.
How's it going?
G-A-M-I-N-G.
You having a good day?
Today is Sunday, people.
There has never existed a more perfect day to play Isaac than on a Sunday.
You know why?
Because you go to church on Sunday.
And church is religion.
And this game is religion.
You know what I mean?
Multiple meanings on that.
Music slash, what is it?
It's GoldenEye, my friend.
On the N64, of course.
It's called Control.
Because I'm in control.
Today we will not lose a single run.
Okay, maybe one run will lose just because it's been a little bit since I played last.
But other than that, it's gonna be flawless.
Perfect.
Immediate.
Yeah.
Challenges?
Yeah, sure.
We'll do some of those.
And greet mode.
And normal mode.
Speed run mode.
Slow mode.
Turtle mode.
Name the mode.
I'll do greet.
Someone's like, fuck, I hate greet.
And it's always like someone out there who loves it and someone who hates it.
I think this game is pretty well balanced for everyone.
You know?
What's up, the Dark Joe?
Maybe you heard, but a PC recomp of Twilight Princess, the second ocarina of time sequel, dropped this week.
It's called Dusk.
You should really check it out.
Yeah, but I... I played a lot of Zelda's lately.
I need to calm down a bit.
I'm definitely gonna play all the Zelda's.
In time.
But yeah, fuck greed.
No, greed is cool.
But I will say, I think normal mode is cooler.
The thing is though, that could be unlocks and greed that I want to get, right?
Also, I got to see what happens when you donate enough money to the stupid machine.
Right?
Basically, there's a lot of reasons for doing a lot of things in this game.
Also, I'm finger dancing right now.
You can't see it, but I am.
I can't not.
God, man, they nailed it with the music in GoldenEye, didn't they?
Like, that had no right to be that good.
Wilma was cooking that up, was making a nice meal.
You said no Isaac this weekend?
Did I?
Fuck.
Yes, I am a liar.
I lied about that.
I am a liar.
I'm sorry.
Well, here we are.
I got to play Isaac.
Time to close the tree.
Yeah, see you guys tomorrow.
I did forget that.
I said that.
Sicko mode, please.
Okay, you got it.
We'll do sicko mode.
We'll be trying Jacob and Esau today.
I did that last time.
What do you mean?
I had a great run with those.
That was awesome.
Oh, yeah.
Make another apology video.
Maybe.
Maybe I'll do another apology video.
Once in a while, you got to get the things out of your system, you know?
Apologize for all the horrible things you've been doing.
Such as not playing Isaac.
Enough of that.
Stop!
We're going for repentance.
We're trying to achieve a repentance today.
Look at that image.
What do we start off with here?
Honestly, I think we should start with a greed mode.
Yeah, greed is good.
Let's start with a greed mode.
We can play Jacob and Esau in greed.
Just to see what's going on, you know.
Learn the ropes.
All that sort of thing.
Let's do it.
I'm going in, baby.
Right, so, okay, so you can actually dislodge these people by walking into things.
You see that?
Now we're more stacked.
This is the key, I think, to this character or these characters.
So, wait a minute.
I'm assuming top left is Jacob, bottom right is Esau.
Weird name, by the way.
But one blue heart, one red heart.
So, I wonder what happens when one of them dies.
Okay, lost some damage there.
That's probably okay.
Oh, no, we got unstacked.
Wait, I need to... There we go.
Okay, you ready?
Here we go.
I mean, is this just having to double the damage, right?
I mean, this is nice.
I like this.
It seems like a very strong character.
Whoop.
As long as you don't get separated, then it's bad.
Well, it depends what happens when one of them dies, right?
You don't really know.
Oh, man, it feels good to play this again already.
It's like I didn't even leave, you know?
Like, I've been in this game forever.
Muscle memory is instantly back.
Whoop, careful now.
Okay, we're a little slow here.
It happens.
I got hit.
Both of us got hit somehow.
Wait, why are there two hearts in the blue heart down there now?
In the bottom right.
That's weird.
That don't make no sense.
Yup, see Daisy.
Oh my god.
Yo, this character is strong.
Are you kidding me?
This is good.
I thought it would be like a crutch, you know?
I have two people, but it's just double the fun.
Double the damage.
All right, 17 coins.
What?
Oh, okay, okay, I see.
We can destroy this, I guess.
Nothing?
Thanks.
Tarot cloth?
Do we have any items?
No, no items.
So, a snack.
I wonder.
Is that gonna give both of us extra HP or just one of us?
Or maybe the one I touch it with.
So wait, if I... I'm gonna do a little experiment here.
I'm gonna just... No!
I didn't mean to walk into that.
That was a mistake.
I'm gonna dislodge that a little bit.
There we go.
Now, I'm gonna... Let me see.
Moms lock it.
Heal for half a red heart whenever Isaac unlocks something.
Converts half a red heart drops into a hole.
Ooh.
Yo, that's actually pretty good.
Only five?
So wait, if I walk into that with... Oh wait, how do I do this without...
Okay, so that means Jacob has that now.
Faded Polaroid.
Gains camouflage for a few seconds.
Well, this is just gonna be one of us, right?
Can be used to... Whoa!
That's right, by the way.
We gotta open a strange door today.
And I know exactly how to do it, by the way.
I know exactly how to do it.
But that's not here.
That's not here.
That's later.
So, if I walk into this with this guy... Oh, I don't have enough money.
Okay, fine.
Alright, let's go back to combat.
Let me just stack them.
There we go.
Restack in the corner.
Reconfigured.
This is good.
Don't step on the button.
Alright, this is like playing Yulith just better.
A lot better.
Sick.
Another one.
Lord of Flies.
I forget his actual name.
Something with Flies.
Duke of Flies.
That's the one.
What even is a Duke?
Someone who owns land, I presume.
Someone fancy.
Does this look like a guy who owns land?
Doesn't look like it to me.
Money!
Oh, I gotta get a key.
We gotta get a key.
What is that?
Little Monstro, ain't he cute?
Following Familia that charges and releases scattered bursts of tears.
Okay, that's kind of cool.
But wait, let me try something.
If I drop this thing now, and then I walk into it with this character.
Ah, we're gonna be switching this around depending on who has the least HP.
Okay, reconfiguration.
I wonder if Jacob counts as a Familiar.
Probably not.
Oh, wait, we got it.
Oh, there's a charge attack on this little guy.
Oh, that's kind of cool.
Dude, I got a lot of DPS here.
Okay, but wait, now we can choose, I guess.
Which one to... Let me see, Dark Matter.
I guess what's here is to stacks with both of us, or works on both of us.
I think I want... Oh, dude, I can take one on each.
Let me reconfigure.
Oh, sorry, I didn't mean to do that.
Like that.
I think I'll take this on... I think this is... Not Isaac, but Jacob.
Let's put that on him then.
You are gonna grab... Ah, but wait, that's an active, isn't it?
Hmm... I don't know about that.
Let's try and pick it up.
Okay, so how do I use that?
I guess Q, because it's in the bottom right?
I'm not gonna do it yet, but I assume so.
Let's see here.
16 coins.
I think you need some more HP.
There we go.
Reconfigure.
Oh, we're done here.
Ah, in that case... I don't know.
I think we just move on.
Yeah, why not?
This is a very weird character.
Characters.
It's probably gonna be some kind of crazy combo you can make with this.
Catacombs.
Let's see what we have.
Minimush.
So, let me see the stats here.
So, I think that the indented stats are Isao, bottom right, and the non-indented stats are Jacob.
This gives speed and range.
They have pretty much the same range.
Speed is... Oh, we have the same speed, okay.
So, I guess we're both gonna get this speed, right?
Size down.
Is that just one of us?
It's just one of us.
Okay, okay, that's funny.
But we both gained the speed.
Now, one of us has more range.
I'm glad I did that on the character with the fear effect.
Launch.
Oh, that's actually pretty good.
PhD.
Oh, dude, full pill mode.
Yo, that could be awesome.
You guys have this.
Buying a bomb here could be worth it.
Five coins for that.
Let me destroy this.
Sick.
We configure.
Actually, I should be doing that in every room like this.
Okay.
Enjoy that.
I mean, we're still pretty stacked.
Careful, careful.
Reconfigure.
Honestly, going pretty well.
Oh,
wow.
There's a lot of focus.
Oh, man, that was a hard one.
My goodness, 20 coins though.
I need a key.
I can buy the PhD and a key.
Actually, I think I should take lunch.
Because come on.
I mean, we don't find that many pills in greed mode, right?
I feel like that's a rare thing.
I'm gonna buy this.
Wait, that's tears.
That's just gonna affect one of us.
Plus one health is also nice.
And that will take us to two out of three on fungi, which could be nice.
Let's take this though and hit in here.
You know what?
Actually entering a new room is like an automatic reconfigure.
Plus one tears.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Absolutely.
Actually, no, this is horrible.
I will not use this.
Also, I'm gonna try to see if I can use this item.
Okay, so it is Q.
Good to know.
Oh, bastard.
There you go.
He's gonna charge me soon.
Yeah, here comes.
No, not yet.
Oh, close one.
Dude, I'm surprised how well I'm playing, since I haven't played in a couple days, you know.
I still got it.
Very unconfigured right now.
There we go.
Nine coins.
I don't want that mushroom.
Getting HP is big here, I think.
Yeah.
Okay.
I think we just keep destroying.
I figure.
Go.
Oish.
Gonna charge me.
Oh, buddy, buddy, buddy.
Oh, there's a knockback from the familiar volley is actually significant.
I'm gonna use it to push enemies back.
What's that sound?
Oh, that was my familiar barfing.
Sacrificial dagger or... Ooh, Eye of the Occult.
No, that's horrible as well.
What is it with these fucking items here that I don't need?
I think I give this to... Yeah, that's fine.
Jacob, it is.
Teamwork makes its ream work.
So this one.
Orbital knife familiar that deals heavy contact damage and blocks enemy shots.
That could be huge, because I'm pretty much like a double target right now, because I'm twice the size of a normal character, right?
So having things that can prevent taking damage like that could be big.
I'm gonna take it on... Let's actually take it on the other guy.
There we go.
Nine coins.
Wait, that's it for now.
Oh, we can't afford anything else.
We can buy a key, I guess.
Nothing is on sale.
It's so sad.
Could go in here, but that's gonna cost me.
I can't do it.
I got a leaf.
Come on.
Oh man, all these items.
Fine.
Keep going.
I'm trying to think what items would be insane on these.
Down here first.
Spawns all kinds of crap.
Why not?
Purple heart.
Yeah.
I'll take that.
Now we both have a trinket.
Pill time.
Wait, how do I use that?
Oh, you hold... I see.
You hold control.
Speed up!
Nice.
The Empress gives me damage.
Ah, okay.
Key, coin... Actually, I can go in here immediately.
Chance to fire tooth shots that deal... Okay, so who has the most damage?
That's the most luck.
It's also Jacob.
There you go, buddy.
Nice.
Very good.
Destroy this immediately.
And we can use that heal later.
The boomerang.
Throws a boomerang.
Oh, this one is actually pretty good.
The only thing is, like, using actives when you have, like, two characters seems really difficult.
I am immediately drawn to the crackjacks.
Just having more HP, you know, is nice.
It is cheap, though.
Ah, fuck it.
Let's just start.
We configure.
That's for you.
I'm gonna kill that guy, man.
There we go.
Shit.
I'm stuck in a corner.
Oh, my God.
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm not configured.
There we go.
We're stacked again.
Jesus Christ.
Wow.
I didn't even notice we were separated.
Whoa.
Nice.
Big guy.
There
you go.
That's for you.
Oi, oi, oi.
We're... Oh, my God.
We got a stack.
Dude, getting unstacked is actually insanely difficult to deal with.
I have a feeling that if one of us dies, it's over.
None of us can die.
Oh, man.
30 coins, though.
Okay, that's definitely a crackjack for this guy.
Oh, yeah.
Huge, huge.
What's that?
A missing page.
5% chance to deal 80 damage to the room and taking damage.
Now, chromaticon, blackhearts, and drybaby also do this increased damage.
Wow.
I guess Isao is bigger, so he's gonna take more damage.
Oh, shit.
It's a trinket.
In that case, I think I may... No, this is fine.
We're just gonna keep it like this.
This is okay.
Nothing else I want to do in here.
Maybe maybe eat pills.
Nah.
No, no, no.
Keep going.
Wow.
I'm so glad we're stacked right now.
Whoa.
We're a little unstacked.
There we go.
Re-stack.
Good.
Huge.
Oh, my god.
I'm unstacked.
Oh, wow.
Dude, this guy needs to die.
There's small guy down there.
Please kill him.
Oh, we can't die or what?
Oh, god.
Okay, there we go.
There we go.
Fuck me, man.
That was tough.
23 coins.
Need more HP.
Man, I could re-roll.
Then again, I can also just go to the next floor.
Probably better.
I got one bomb, too, in case I want to find a secret room.
Should we gamble?
No.
Go to the next floor in case there's something we need to bomb to get to in the shop.
This is the strategy.
It's good.
Get the little guy.
There we go.
Huge.
Yeah, no problem.
Hey, another demon deal.
Ah.
Wait, multidimensional baby could actually be kind of sick here.
Pentagram.
I mean, that's also good.
Ooh, I think... Let me see.
Let me see.
I think I'm gonna go for the baby, honestly.
Oh, I love that.
Let's see.
Okay, one of us is growing up.
Ah, shit.
The Empress.
I forgot we had that.
Okay, we're both at 2 HP now.
Is what it is.
Okay.
Wish me luck.
This is all like... Our damage is gonna be amplified by this baby.
If we can somehow manage to do it right.
Well, that's the big if.
Everyone's gonna be... Or everything's gonna be relying on that.
Caffeine pill.
We get our speed back.
I think Isao needs to be a little smaller.
Hey.
Balls of steel.
Nice.
Give me that back.
See what we got here.
Oh, is that tech X?
But wait a minute.
How's that gonna... Are we both gonna get the effect?
Dude, we need both of these.
Absolutely.
Let's say that Isao gets this.
Yeah, and then, and then we're gonna start this.
Get the money and start doing the other thing.
Oh, shit.
Wow.
The hell is that?
Who's bombing?
Oh, god.
Kill him.
Oh, this guy up here needs to die immediately.
Reconfigure.
There we go.
Fully configured.
Multidimensional baby doing its thing.
Oh, goodness gracious.
We're going.
Get the corner.
Damage.
We got separated.
Oh, whoa, whoa.
Jesus.
Oh, my god.
Whoo.
Okay, so who has the most damage?
That would be Isao.
I think we give him the... Oh, wait.
One of them has more range.
Yeah, that's Isao as well.
We're gonna give him the goggles.
Okay, I mean, I like it, I think.
What's that?
Mucobicosis via fungus shots.
Stick to enemies.
I mean, that's good.
More and get this one, too.
I think I'm gonna... Oh, definitely bomb that.
No!
I didn't mean to run into that!
Fucking unconfigured state.
Messed with me.
Damn it.
That's gonna happen a lot, I promise you.
I can just see it.
Okay, get in here.
Monstro's lung.
Tears become a charge attack.
Well, in that case, let's just make everything become a charge.
Because two of us is charged right now.
Let's have a third one be charged.
So, we're gonna unconfigure ourselves.
No, wait.
Who's not charging?
Yeah, it's Jacob.
Haha!
Yo, come on.
That's awesome.
Fully charged.
Let's do it.
Hahaha!
Oh, that was it?
We're unconfigured.
It's scary.
Oh, god.
It's a whole freaking army we got here.
Damage is good.
It's very good.
Okay, there's more.
Come on.
Wow.
Yeah, nice.
This is gonna be awkward against the final boss, I'm telling you.
It's gonna feel real bad.
I mean, honestly, this is also pretty good.
That's gonna take me to two out of three on fun.
Ah, but wait a minute.
Do we have separate, what do you call it, metamorphosis stats on these characters?
I guess so, right?
I guess I spread out my fun guy.
Damn.
Are we done here?
Not yet, okay.
Oh my god, it lifts?
Just like that?
Oh, yeah.
Haha, not bad.
Not bad.
No money, though.
Okay, I'm a- you know what?
I'm gonna walk in- how do I- I need to walk in with Jacob first.
I need to- wait.
Show me what's good.
Appill!
Yeah.
Ah, wrong button.
Invested, okay.
Speed up, nice!
We like that.
Let me take this heart.
And I'm not gonna take the other heart.
Man, we're at 14 coins!
Can we somehow get the last?
I guess I could donate a heart here.
Should we do that?
Let me see.
Need to unconfigure.
Okay, one more.
No!
Okay, fine.
Whatever.
Wait, we are super stacked.
Okay, there we go.
Good.
Let's go.
It was not meant to be.
Here we go!
Shield!
Oh, blue fire.
Speedball- wait, if I walk next to that with Jacob.
Ah, speed and shot speed.
Who has the least shot speed?
It's actually Izao, so we gotta give him that.
Now we're a little more aligned.
Not a lot, but a little.
Sci-fly!
That's good, man!
And I think it's better to put it on the big guy, just because it's gonna orbit in a bigger radius, I guess.
Very nice.
There's a whole army we're making here, and I love it.
Ah, we got a bomb this.
No bombs though.
I want to bomb so many things.
What's that?
D10 devolves all enemies in the room into other enemies of lower difficulty.
That is interesting, actually.
Only seven.
I could consider that.
Pause.
Could be nice if I need to reconfigure.
You know?
That could actually be amazing.
On this one, we don't know what is.
I mean, these items are not that cool, I will say.
I think I'm actually gonna take this and then I just go, if I click space, that uses that, right?
Yeah.
Okay, here we go.
Reconfiguration and activate.
This guy needs to die first, cuz he's scary.
Whoa!
Sci-fly already working.
I like it.
I'm gonna go through the baby.
There we go.
Multidimensional attacks are delicious.
I see you down there.
Whoa!
Oh god.
Oh, we're unconfigured!
There you go, stack.
What are we taking damage from?
I used the D10.
Nothing happened.
Oh my god, I can't hit.
Whoa!
Calm down!
Holy shit!
18 coins, though.
This one is starter deck.
No, thanks.
This is it.
I don't like these items, dude!
I don't like them.
I need a bomb.
Maybe that one?
No, it's not.
No, it ain't good, man.
Just keep going.
How did that hit me?
It's messing with me a little bit, that the charge times with these different characters are different.
Okay, we can do one more.
Or we go heal.
Maybe that's worth it.
Yeah, plate safe.
Now the heart spawned.
I'm trying to multidimensional this as much as I can.
Oh yeah, that was good.
We're still stacked.
Configuration good.
Nice, solid.
27 coin arenas.
I will save it for the next floor.
Wait, is next floor the end?
We also gotta save money, though, to donate.
Almost forgot about that.
Let's not buy anything.
Wow, good damage.
That was nice.
Oh god, freaking spiders.
Reconfigure.
Solid.
Not bad.
Door opened.
Oof.
Okay, we take a look.
Uh, okay, okay, that's nice, actually.
I'm gonna grab those hearts.
Okay, so we're gonna grab that on Jacob.
Actually, just Jacob.
There we go.
And this one is black powder.
No, I don't like that.
Guppy's paw is... I mean, no, no, it ain't worth it, man.
It ain't worth it.
Okay, so this is the day before the last day, or whatever you want to say.
Let's play.
The shop!
Um, don't accidentally buy things, careful.
Consolation price?
Nah.
Oh, wait, what?
Dude, I need a bomb.
Where the bomb's at?
This is a weird floor.
Nice.
Oh, wrong way.
They're like mini-greets.
Sci-fly is doing his job.
I need the multidimensional baby here.
Oh, come on.
Oh, god.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, we got separated!
Stack, stack, stack!
We're stacked again.
Kinda-ish.
Oi!
Sci-fly!
Wow!
Oh, hoi!
Come on, multidimensional babies.
Line it up!
There we go.
Good line-up.
Oh, beautiful!
Nice.
Keep going.
I clicked again!
I'm an idiot.
It was a mistake.
Stack it up, nice.
Oh, god!
Stack, stack, stack, stack, stack!
What?
Scary.
I devolved.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, nice.
51 coins.
And not a lot of HP.
I may have to buy a little bit of HP here.
You need some.
That's pretty much it.
I could re-roll these items.
If I wanted to.
No, we're gonna save the money.
Wait, we can't leave yet.
Right, we're not done.
Stack it.
There we go.
Oh, wow.
Oi!
Holy shit, boss!
Whoa!
Wow!
Oh, we lost one black heart there.
Not great.
Can I leave now?
I can leave now if I want to, but why would I- wait, why would I press this button again?
Let's just do it.
It's probably good, right?
Wait, are we separated?
What's happening?
I'm taking mega damage!
What the fuck is going on?
Oh, I'm stepping on crap.
Oh, my god.
Impossible to keep track of.
I need to buy more.
Wait, there's a key up here now.
What?
Why?
I don't understand that.
Okay, well, we're leaving.
Can't get any of this, unfortunately.
Here we go.
This is gonna be a tough one.
This is gonna be a sci-fi operation.
We have to remember to use the Bible and the Empress.
Wake up, son.
Oh, god.
Jesus.
Well, we got some money there.
That's nice.
Hey, lock up.
Okay, cool.
Here we go.
Maximum stack and focus now.
Ultra greed.
I have come in here with a lot of money.
I'm ready, son.
I'm ready.
Kill those coins.
Oh, god.
Whoa.
I'm kind of scared.
Oh, shit.
I need to stack a little bit.
There we go.
Honestly, I don't care if he heals.
At this point, it's whatever.
Oh, god.
Whoa.
Yep, yep, yep.
Kill him!
The multi-dimensional baby ain't lining up for me.
That's because we're not lined up.
Hold on.
We gotta reconfigure.
There we go.
What's with these keys?
Oh, wait, he's... Oh!
I'm understanding that... Oh, I'm fucked here.
There's no way I can survive.
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
So, when one of them dies, you're dead.
Shit.
Dude, you gotta kill the keys.
Otherwise, they open the doors.
I don't like this character.
I mean, it's good, but it's just annoying to play with.
Random.
Good old random.
Sure.
If you insist.
If you insist, my lady.
I shall dance for you.
Okay, we're going full min-max here, dude.
No speedrun here.
Full min-max.
Oh, what's that?
Those are... Oh!
Copies of the Bible toy.
I think I'm gonna give that to Jacob.
Big J.
Good.
Man, the extra DPS is actually kind of helpful right now.
God, I hate these enemies.
They may actually be my most hated enemy in the game right now.
The guys that pop up and go bloop!
They're actually okay compared to these guys.
Anything good in here?
We got PhD.
Pill run, maybe.
Oh, wait.
I was about to say, wait, why does Jacob have so much HP?
But that's because we just picked the thing up that gave us a lot of HP.
Shits make sense.
I guess we have a shared item pool there with the bombs and stuff.
Never really thought about it, but I guess that's the case.
Thank you.
Okay.
I mean, why not?
Let's go.
We can actually go into the curse room with the guy with a lot of blue HP.
Oh, fuck you.
Just hide up here.
Kill the little guys.
And charge.
There we go.
Stack up.
Oh, god.
Nice.
Yeah!
Uh, squeezy.
Oh, we gave that to Esau then.
Balance out the hearts.
Wait, he only has one red heart?
What the fuck?
Yo.
Hold on, we got to go to the curse room.
Yeah, we got to find HP up for that guy, for sure.
Good.
Subviber!
How does that work?
Do we both get to fly, or just one of those, or what?
There we go.
I think we're done here.
Yeah.
Oh, we got three three bombs, actually.
Do we have any tinted rocks?
Oh, we do!
Oh.
Yo, we played... oh!
Extra bombs!
Interesting.
So, bomb strategies could be really good here against the bosses.
There's no way I can afford any of this, unfortunately, but that's okay.
No tinted rocks here, or here.
Uh, do I use my key to go in there?
That place is more dangerous than going down, and this character is kind of difficult.
I'm gonna go down.
I don't want to waste my key.
So, now we should be in...
Oh, cellar.
I was about to say catacombs.
Oh, yeah, cellar.
Oh, god.
Keys and bombs.
Oi, oi, oi.
What
do we have here?
Not this!
Are you kidding me?
What is it with this fucking luck?
Yeah, I'm not taking that.
You can suck it.
Stag it.
Ooh, pills.
I misclicked, but okay, I guess only one of us flies.
Got it.
Nice!
Good shit.
Come here.
Another key is big.
Ah, with two characters, huh?
Hold on, I can do this.
We are aligned.
We are lined up!
Oh!
Wait, who's, uh, okay, you're there.
Wait, I'm in trouble here now.
Oh, it wasn't even good!
Okay, line up now.
We're not lined up correctly.
Come on, Tars.
Yep, yep.
Ja, fuck off!
Dude, I hate this.
I'm not doing it.
Killer.
Nice.
Boss!
Uh, yeah, why not?
We can do that now.
Okay, then.
Do your thing.
I know you want to.
What the?
That's new.
Bro, what is that?
Why does he do that suddenly?
Okay, so who has the least damage?
That's definitely Jacob.
There you go.
That's for you.
Uh, we can't take that.
Uh, I think I may go full angel, honestly.
Because donating hearts when you have two characters is a little... I don't know about that, son.
You know?
Uh, let's keep exploring.
Fuck the demons.
I don't want it.
I reject it.
Pride!
He's gonna do the bzzzt, right?
Yep, there it is.
Ooh, good damage!
And two bombs?
Yo!
Let's not forget the fact that we can fly in case we need to.
Uh, you know what?
I have a feeling.
We're gonna bomb here to get rid of these and maybe look for a...
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Line up.
Now we have money for a shop if we find one.
Well, a little bit.
Yo, wait a minute!
I can...
Dude, I just had a genius idea.
Check this out.
We can bomb two places at once like this.
Huh?
Hey!
The question is, do I want to?
Probably not.
Dude, calm down!
Wow.
Nice.
Shop acquired.
Oh, it's on sale.
Ooh, uh, give that to Jacob.
Sure.
Actually, not bad.
A soul heart on the start of each floor is nice.
It's probably just gonna happen to Jacob, though.
Okay, so watch this.
I'm actually gonna do this.
Oh, shit.
Big galaxy brain.
Nah, no stepping.
It ain't good.
I'm leaving.
I feel like this was a solid second floor.
Could get that pill, but nah.
It's okay.
Down we go.
Cheers.
Was that the razor or something?
I think that was a razor.
Ah, it's gonna push all the coins out of there.
That's good.
Got a stack like this instead.
There we go.
Nice.
Could go in there.
I'm actually gonna do it.
Ooh, am I glad I did.
Look at that.
That's the pentagram.
Yeah, who needs that?
Probably Esau, actually.
And then we walk in with... I think this guy.
Yeah, that's fine.
Because he's the one that has... Let me see.
Oh, I can't see who has the items.
Wait, Seraphim, two out of three.
That's nice.
Wait, how do I see the pentagram?
Wait, hold this and then...
No, that all tapped me.
Whoops.
Hold this and then... No.
I don't fucking know.
Uh, we're not stacked.
There we go.
I could get in there, actually.
Do I want to?
All of that just to use a key to get a chest?
I don't think so, man.
Feel smart.
Just keep exploring.
Oh, I
just realized I can fly.
If I wanted that.
Oh, no, don't get stacked.
Okay, what do we got?
Shot speed down.
Fuck it.
It's okay.
Six coins to my name.
Dude, this is actually huge.
Broken watch on this character?
I think I'm going to try and save for that.
I could also destroy... Oh, you know what?
Dude, I'm doing it.
This is the play.
On which character do we put it on?
Probably...
Yeah, that's fine.
We can't afford this anyway, so we take that.
Now we need to start counting soon.
We don't know where the boss is.
Is that the razor?
That's the thing we saw in the dream.
Oh, we don't know what this is?
Golden razor.
Pain from game.
Plus five coins.
Consumes five coins to grant a plus 1.2 damage bonus for the current room.
Can stack multiple times.
So it's like the ultimate, what do you call it?
Money equals power.
Yo, okay.
I mean, if we get rich, then I'll keep it in mind, yeah?
I think for sure there's not a secret room on the right.
I can fly here.
I think I'm gonna do it.
I can't see the preview of the item.
Death.
Right, okay.
Yeah, that's the one with 40 damage.
Let's do this.
Oh, did
I just take damage from something?
Oh man, the HP situation is looking grim.
So I think this is gonna be a slow down room now.
No, maybe that next one then.
Stack it.
This one.
Yeah.
Okay, so that means we don't know where the boss is yet.
This is one.
Still at one.
Two.
Oh, it's gonna, it's gonna be perfect, actually.
If we can avoid getting hit by this crap up there.
Ahh, fuck you!
Eish!
I know you want to shoot me.
Come on, good.
Are we done?
Not yet.
Okay, okay, good.
So, we're at two now.
This is gonna be three.
We're gonna get slowed down on boss room.
Hopefully not sped up.
Here we go.
Pestilence!
You're slow, son.
Got shot out of the way.
He's gonna charge or something?
No, no.
Sick.
Never stood a chance.
No, not this item!
I
could have been an HP up.
What a waste.
72% angel chance.
So, this is good.
Except if we take damage now.
It's a very real possibility.
Whoa!
No more charging.
I have a buffer on both, actually.
Not a lot, but I have it.
Oh, shit.
What the hell?
Wow.
Man, they're tanky.
Come on, move away from there.
Good.
I'm gonna let this guy shoot one more time.
There we go.
Solid.
Let's see, one, two, three.
This is gonna be slowed down now.
Let's do this one.
Okay.
Eight.
That's gonna count for one, I think.
But I have 14 coins.
I'd rather save them.
I guess we get one more coin and we can go to the shop.
Oh my god.
Stack, stack, stack, stack, stack.
Come on.
How are you supposed to do this?
Whoa!
Stack it up again.
That's a crazy room.
Yep.
Whoa!
Let's see.
One, two, three.
Ah, shit.
We may not be able to time this with the boss.
It's gonna be slowed down now.
Ha!
They ran into the fire.
Yeah, one second.
15 coins.
Still haven't found a treasure room, though.
Maybe I should save my key.
Never mind, I have two keys.
Stack it.
Wait, so what do we have?
Uh, coupon.
That's nice.
Oh, that's also nice.
I need to take this, though.
Yeah, fuck this golden razor.
Nah, I mean, it's okay.
But I wanted this one, for sure.
Blue map.
I'll come back with more charge and we can maybe do it.
So that was one.
I think I may have to go back and do a two.
No, I don't need two.
We can do this now.
Two.
This is gonna be hell.
Patience.
Oh, god.
Oh, no, we're not stacked.
Oh, man, this layout is gonna be fucking annoying on this character.
I need open spaces, you know.
Ah!
At least he hit Jacob there.
Okay, we have a three and a four.
We can do this.
We can make the boss room slow.
It's gonna help a lot.
You know what?
I have a feeling right here.
Yep.
A pill.
Ah, great.
Last shot, Speeds.
No, thanks.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Let me blow that guy up.
Sometimes you get chances from that.
Hey, look at that, plus five.
Am I gaming or what?
So wait, that was actually the third.
So now we gotta go back.
This counts as three, right?
Now we do boss.
And that's gonna be slowed.
What happens if we get so far away that we can't see each other?
What happens then?
Wait, he's not slowed.
I miscounted?
Unless the secret room doesn't count.
Oh, shit.
No!
Standing on the crab on the floor.
Oh, my God.
There goes my fucking angels.
Dude!
Oh, wait.
Oh, the other guy had no HP.
I keep looking up in the left.
I'm like, oh, I'm fine.
That's annoying.
Well...
What are we gonna get?
Laceras.
I feel like it's always the same characters this randomizer lands on.
Come here.
So, Rainbow is gonna heal me.
I'm actually gonna save that then.
Kinda want a speedrun.
I'm getting impatient now.
Steven.
But I ain't got nothing.
Okay.
Oh, he was very close there.
Little Steven is angry.
I gotta get him into a cheese configuration.
Maybe kill Big Steve first.
There we go.
Come here.
Almost.
I think he may be too fast for the cheese configuration.
No, I got hit!
Can I actually?
No, I cannot actually.
But I can do this.
Ah, one of them fell back in.
Oh, wait, I have a pill.
Hey!
Amnesia.
Oh, well.
Destroyed the rainbow poop.
Gimme tinted rocks.
There we go.
Maybe I'll step, actually.
This run could be a step run.
Do, do, do, do.
Oh, I can't see the map, of course.
Ace of spades, chance of finding a card.
Uh, card to chest, tinted rocks.
I like pills more.
But I guess...
That's fine.
Why not?
Let's do it.
You can always take it off, right?
I don't like these items.
I do actually like this item.
A little buffer.
The intruder.
Oh, that one's weird.
But fine.
Not a big fan of that one.
You know, I'm actually kind of curious.
I wonder what this will say when you play, uh...
Jacob and Esau.
You know?
Like, how are they gonna...
Like, what are they gonna write?
Go down.
I would say that's a successful first floor.
I have no regrets on that one.
I guess it's randomized whether or not little Steven is gonna shoot homing tears or the shotgun.
Oh, god.
Yeah, we just run past.
How on earth did you hit me?
I was in full motion.
I guess they do predictive shooting.
Oh, I sense a secret room here, guys.
Actually, never mind.
Maybe the little Steven shoots these tears whenever it's off cooldown.
So, right now.
See that?
And when it's off cooldown, he shoots the homing ones.
Kind of nice for these hit and run strategies.
Sweet.
Oh, I got no key.
No way.
Watch this.
I don't dare from this side.
Maybe here.
No!
What?
Okay, well, that's unlucky.
Down we go.
I really thought that was gonna be a secret room.
These guys first, and then these guys are gonna explode.
Yep.
I've got these floors down, you know?
We can go back.
Yeah, I'm going back.
We gotta get the treasure room.
I want... I want...
What do I want from the treasure room?
I want the one that makes me...
Is it the tech one?
Wait, tractor beam.
First one, tears, range.
Oh, it's that one.
I think, yeah, it's fine.
I mean, better than not having it, I guess.
Sometimes some of these tear-affecting buffs actually make things worse.
I look like Bane.
Go here.
Oh, are you slowed?
That's too bad.
A beggar.
I'm not gonna waste my key on that.
Got no money anyway.
The tractor beam, you gotta sort of change your playstyle around it.
Because I'm no longer trying to get these diagonal shots, you know?
Now it's all about being on target.
Like a laser beam.
Steven's gonna help you a lot.
Dude, I have pretty good damage.
What the hell?
Whoa, wait, how?
Is it just little Steven?
That's crazy.
Mom's coin purse.
I don't like that one.
But I mean, pills are good.
I'm excited.
It's infested.
Hey, there it is.
Now we go in here.
Ouija board.
Ooh, I like that one.
We could also take a Guppy's paw.
Dude, I feel like this item should not be a demon item.
Because it is so incredibly mid.
Because you gotta sacrifice one HP for that, which sucks ass.
You know?
So I don't know.
I don't want it.
Fuck that shit item.
It's actually less than mid.
It's like, why do I even wanna...
Like, even if they gave me money, I wouldn't take it.
Like, even if I get a health up, I wouldn't take it.
Actually I would, because then you get a free three black cards, but you know.
Yeah.
It just seems so bad.
Hey, here's one fish, you know.
Or three fish you can eat right now, instead of having to learn to fish for the rest of your life.
What would you prefer?
Obviously to fish for the rest of my life.
Okay.
Oh, sorry.
Wake up.
And the slowing effect is actually kinda good.
Helps a lot.
Is that actually Steven doing that?
Homing tears.
Changing...
Wait, what is causing the slow down?
Changing the direction of the beam.
It's not this one.
Fires quads shots of... Oh, it's this one!
Ahh!
I see.
That's... Oh, wait!
Oh, it never was Steven that shot those.
It was me.
I get it now.
That makes so much more sense.
Because I was legitimately confused by that.
Because that's not what it said, you know.
But there it is.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
Slow them down.
That's scary.
We have minus one unlocked for some reason.
I don't want to go in there.
I have no money.
I'm a broke ass bitch in this run.
This is crazy.
Haven't found nothing.
Come here.
The sun!
Wow!
Okay, let's just do this then.
He wants hearts.
Not gonna happen, brother.
Not when I'm in the market for some demons.
Okay.
Get snowed, nerd.
Oh, you have spectral tears!
Almost forgot about that.
Yo.
That's nice.
Slow them!
Oh, I guess it doesn't work on bosses.
We cannot take damage now.
Oh, God.
That's for you.
Oh, yeah!
You like the bomb?
Big, big, big the bomb.
2.5 range.
Yeah.
That's good.
Very good.
Wait, do I have infinite range with a tractor beam?
No, okay, okay.
I'm just wondering.
Treasure room has not been found.
It has been found, but I haven't entered for some reason.
What the fuck's all that about?
Huh?
Why wouldn't I have done that?
That don't even make no sense.
Thanks.
Papa fly.
Fires once per second with I6-2 damage.
And I6-2 effects, maybe?
No?
Okay.
I was hoping for a secondary tractor beam coming out of that fly.
Coins, eh?
No.
I think I'm actually just gonna go.
No, no, no, no.
We clear everything.
You never know where you're gonna find, right?
Oh, look at this here.
A pill, which does?
Okay, well, that was...
It's a good idea to use it anyway, right?
So now we know what that does.
For the future.
Got... whoa!
And gets slowed.
Kill it fast.
Nice.
It's slowing.
Also slows projectiles.
It is incredibly good.
It may be one of the best status effects you can have in the game.
Or like debuffs on the enemy.
It is incredible.
I think our job is done here.
We could go for that pill.
We don't know what it is.
Nice!
Back to zero.
Very good.
Definitely worth a bomb.
And let's go out of here.
Solid third floor.
No complaints.
I'm not gonna go... Oh, wait, I should have gone in there, actually.
I had two bombs.
Whoops.
It's fine.
So what do we get here?
Flooded caves.
And a lot of demon chants.
I mean, he just did nothing.
More luck!
Whoa.
I'm trying to think what I want to do in this run.
What have I not done?
I think we're too slow for the speedrun.
At this point.
Oh, I know what we're gonna do.
Oh, dude, I know what we're gonna do.
We're gonna find a way to leave the...
What's it called?
The fucking... the uterus, you know?
And then we're gonna go to the special door.
Whoa!
That was close.
This is the main objective of the run.
Come here.
Dude, the tractor beam is killing it.
Guess I'm going left.
Like, even against these guys, the slow is, like, so good.
Solid.
I made it dark.
Can't do that.
Oh, no.
That was actually huge the way I handled that.
Sweet.
Increases max health, yo!
Love it.
Ghost baby.
Special cheers.
Yes, join the party.
Two out of three on that now.
Now I'm slowly getting money.
Maybe it's time.
School bag, perhaps.
Could also blow up the refresh thingy.
We need to.
Unbelievable.
That was terrible, man.
Give me that.
I forgot what you do.
Oh, my gosh.
Killing fast.
Not the consolation prize.
Fine.
Okay, a little bit of speed is actually not that bad, I guess.
It'll do.
I mean, it's going solid, you know, except that one mistake just before.
I think this may be a secret room right here.
Let me check the other side.
Never mind, never mind.
Not a secret room.
Maybe here.
Guess I'll check from this side.
But this is a narrow room.
Maybe that is different.
We need to see it in action, you know.
Let me see.
Okay, nothing, but that could just be coincidence, right?
It's not here.
I don't know.
Could maybe be up in this room?
Two bombs left.
Damn it.
Okay, I'll move on.
Or I get this chest.
No, we're going to take damage from that.
No good.
You know what we could do, actually?
We could get these coins.
No, we can't.
I was going to say we need 15 for the school bag.
Okay, you know what?
I'm going to risk it here.
Okay, that's 14.
Can we get one more?
Maybe if I blow this guy up.
But that's my last bomb.
Ahhh!
I mean, if you think about it, I don't have any actives anyway right now.
But I could have, right?
Like, maybe if we find some really good actives later.
Maybe it's better to save the money at this point.
Fuck it, let's just go.
I don't care.
Damn it!
Actually, I'm very happy about it.
If I had picked up the school bag, I bet your ass.
We would never find a single active in this run.
Same.
Gotta love the spectral cheers.
Do I want that?
Can I even get that?
Not right now.
Give me, like, 99 coins.
Oi!
Could get a buffer there if I have some bombs.
Dude, this is insanity!
Insane room!
One bomb.
And now it doesn't matter with the buffer anyway.
Too late.
Whoopsie daisy!
Always kind of risky running through enemies like that, but sometimes you gotta do it.
More keys.
And this door opens!
Why?
I don't have a blue heart!
Maybe it's like if you find the room before the boss room has been found.
Then...
I pulled that out of my ass just now, but fuck, I'm gonna write it down.
Maybe finding the room before discovering boss room?
I can't spell.
I have no clue, man.
I am so freaking lost.
Oh my god.
Oh, that's a friend.
I mean, the spider jumped off my head and now it's doing work.
Yeah, alright.
Wait, why am I a little...
Oh my god, I'm so tiny?
Is that what happens when the spider jumps off and becomes this little dude?
I guess they didn't have a character model for Isaac with no head.
Awwww!
Okay.
There's still one heart I can grab.
Uh, Grant's Flights?
Ooh.
Maybe there's a room where I want to use that.
Maybe to get through the curse room without taking damage?
Let's just remember that we have it.
Solid.
Go!
Very low demon percent, but it is for this.
That's for you!
You like that?
That's for you as well.
Aw, man.
This guy likes to jump.
Why do I keep falling for that?
Just never be horizontal to him.
I guess that's the rule.
Yeah, he can't shoot down.
And he kills his friends with that, too.
Yeah, I think I figured this guy out.
Question mark!
Speedball, speed and shot up.
Not that exciting.
Still no treasure room.
That saddens me greatly.
Yeah, just keep walking into me one by one.
That's good.
I like seeing that.
Well, she lined up for me there.
Parasitoid!
Egg tears, but there's more, right?
Egg sac tears to spawn a blue spider.
Each sac tear also slows enemies, so even more slowing.
And spawn a small pool of slowing creep.
Increases with the lock.
Okay, we have one lock, though.
That's good.
Oh, my God.
What?!
Bro!
Oh, wait, I have spectral tears.
I gotta use that.
How did you hit me, man?!
I was behind the rock!
How did that just happen?!
Bullshit, I was like, I'm gonna save my son!
Cuz I'm behind the rocks!
Nah, man.
Bullshit.
That's some bullshit right there.
I have no idea how he managed to hit me.
Well, I'm not using the sun.
Not until I have half an HP.
I'd rather die with it in hand!
No, don't go in there.
Keys?
No.
If you had said coins.
And that's a different story.
We lost an HP, though.
Those bombs can be scary.
Actual spiders have helped me a lot here.
I can't even speak English.
Okay, we've pretty much cleared this entire floor.
The hell do you want?
Yeah, let's get out of here.
There is a flying mechanism we can utilize.
Maybe to see what that card is?
Why not, actually?
Let's do it.
Is there anything I can fly to in here, perhaps?
No?
I'm gonna check out that card.
But is it really gonna be better than the sun?
Okay, well.
I got 26 coins.
Ah, but the shop is empty.
Sucks.
I'm leaving.
Oh, uh...
Ah, shit.
The sun.
I wanna get in here.
I wanna do this.
It's the price you pay.
Mossorium.
100% angel chance.
Uh, yeah, actually.
Heal me up.
Could also get a buffer here.
I'm lucky.
Oh, one last bomb.
Come on, please, buffer me.
God, I hate that.
That's terrible.
There goes the angel.
It was nice knowing ya.
Dude, I can literally not see where my character is.
So fucking tiny.
Come here.
You're not gonna change direction, are you?
You are.
Wow.
Can you please just die?
Thank you.
Now, what is this?
It is not good.
Wait, what?
Oh, I can't shoot.
I was cursed.
This guy needs to die.
There we go.
Need some coins.
Dude, I nailed it.
Whoa!
Come on, buffer me.
Not that it matters anymore, actually.
Yeah, fuck it.
But getting some extra HP, you know.
Look to La Luna.
Please, it's the chance of lock-based shots to be fired.
Wait, do I have any of those?
I think I have one.
Yeah, that one.
Chance to fire Exact tiers.
Um, yeah, actually.
I don't like the other one I had anyway.
Okay.
Take us.
Not bad.
Something else, though?
Okay, I'm going to save the rest of my money in case we get a shot.
Wait, is this technically the shot?
No, this is a secret room, right?
Yeah.
It looked like a shot for a bit.
The range on that is crazy!
Thank you very much.
Wow, he exploded in a big pool of red.
What are you doing?
Oi, oi, oi.
Teleports to boss room?
Uh...
Okay, fuck it.
Just do it.
I feel like this run isn't a shitter anyway at this point.
Go for it, man.
Here, here's a bomb for you.
Of course you disappeared!
God damn it.
What's happening?
I don't like that.
What's hitting me?
I can't tell which spiders are evil and which spiders are good.
Are we still... are we fine?
Take it, quick.
What's this?
Huh?
Wait, I have a... I have a green heart.
What the fuck is that?
I have no idea.
But it's gone now.
No, not fire.
Okay, get in here.
Pay to play.
Dude, I feel like these items I've been getting today are just boring as fuck, man.
Like, nothing good, man.
Whatever, just take it.
Wait, we gotta heal.
I can't reach that.
Honestly, just move on.
Ah, just go.
Get out of here.
Next floor, please.
A hundred percent demon, but watch.
It's gonna go to zero in just exactly seven seconds.
Or not.
Nice.
Brain pops out.
Oi, oi, oi.
Kind of nailed that.
Wow.
I think I got him.
I'm excited.
Why not?
I'm very excited.
Ooh, look at this here, guys.
Soil.
Occasion of the boss room.
After defeating the floor's boss, activate the sun.
That is nice.
So we actually want to go to the boss fast with this.
This is the strategy now.
Immediately boss every floor.
Let's go find the boss.
What's that?
Ta-ha.
Man, I've been unlucky with the pills in this run.
But it happens.
Boss here.
Oh, wait, the boss is revealed.
Of course.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay.
Plus range?
No, thanks.
I guess it connects via here.
A black hole has appeared in the basement.
Go!
That sounds nice.
Wait, how am I actually getting to that boss?
It's going to be from here, then.
This map is trolling me.
Oh, God.
Whoa.
The excited pill is kind of funny.
Dude, how do I get to the fucking boss?
I was like, there's no way it's going to...
Where is my character?
I can't see my fucking character, man.
They really need to do something about that.
Fucking give me an outline or a red arrow or something.
So I know where the fuck my playable character is in the game.
It's so stupid.
A ridiculous way to take damage if you don't even know where your character is.
Fucking retarded stuff.
Doesn't make any sense, man.
How has nobody complained about that for like 15 years or however long this game has been out?
Just kill me.
Take me out of my misery.
Fuck me, man.
Go again.
I can't stand that.
It's so annoying to lose because of not being able to see your character.
It's just horrible.
But this is kind of a crazy room, though.
First room...
I kind of want to find a black hole.
Come here.
I wonder if you actually have enough time to push that bomb towards any place meaningful.
I guess what you got to do is...
So when the room is about to end and you clear it, right?
You sort of know that something will spawn, maybe, like a heart or a bomb.
And then you have to sort of, before that happens, get into a position and say, Okay, so maybe over here is where I want the bomb to go.
So you go like this and just quickly push it, you know?
But you got to be frickin' fast with that.
That's not easy.
It is doable, I guess.
I think it's over.
Bad start.
There we go!
But now we need HP.
I forgot what Kane's deal was.
Wasn't the guy with the extra damage when you take damage yourself?
I think that may have been Samson.
What is that?
I guess it's some kind of eternal heart, but it's not eternal.
It's like... I don't know what it is.
Shooting continuously in one direction gradually increases.
This one is actually massive.
I like that one.
We can even charge it up before we go into a room.
Yo, that's actually kind of the strategy.
You do like this?
Ah, but as soon as you change direction, right?
Yeah, okay.
You got to stay committed then.
You got to stay on one path.
Ah, steam sail.
It's way too expensive.
These guys I actually don't even recognize.
I have no idea what they do.
Just jump around.
Okay, let's try not to take damage now because we have this weird heart.
I want to see what it does.
It's giving me...
It should be doable without taking damage.
As long as I just play it safe.
He's coming from that side.
Okay.
Don't get stuck on the rocks.
Don't mess up at the end.
Cheese configuration is maybe coming in here.
Oh, God.
Oh, we almost had it.
There it is.
Oh, and the cheese hits just right.
0.2 by 5 range or 2.5.
Nice.
That's huge.
This floor has been pretty good, I will say.
Not going to go in the, what's it called, downpour.
We're taking the normal last path here.
It's a burning base.
Wait, my heart didn't do anything.
I was expecting something to happen.
Looks like a rotted heart or something.
Overgrown heart.
Super colossus heart.
Something like that.
Dice room.
That's where they make battlefield.
People don't know that, but it's true.
Come here.
These rooms scare me.
Because it feels like I'm on a timer.
Like, when they start getting close to me, you know, it's going to be really hard to get away from them.
Not going to go in there.
I just enjoy being able to see my character now.
Like, fuck that other noise where you become a tiny little fucking thing that is indistinguishable, by the way, from enemies, because it's an enemy model.
So stupid.
I can't actually believe it.
Like, horrible design.
Give me that.
Okay, down.
Yowie!
Oh, God.
There goes my black heart.
Whoa.
Dude, I got to play perfect here.
Oh, Jesus.
We may have to bomb them.
Fuck.
I was hoping he would charge me there.
Come on!
Why is he not charging me?
Okay, there it comes.
Play it safe.
Okay.
Caffeine pill.
That's good.
Ooh, nice.
We also have this.
False PhD.
Or money.
Inverts most good pill effects into...
Nah, I don't want that.
I don't like the bad pill effects.
If anything...
Honestly, I don't want any of this.
Fuck that.
Let's go back to the dice room.
I want to see what that does.
I also have one bomb to get this key if I need to.
I don't think I should.
Okay, wait, two.
What's that?
Question mark, we don't know.
Let's keep doing it until we understand it.
So, let's see here.
Two coins, two bombs, two keys.
These three items.
Stats.
Huh.
So, everything became sort of dark for a second.
I wonder if that has something to do with the boss.
Is it going to change the boss?
Wait.
Or did it just spawn this?
1.93 tears, less range.
Tears turn yellow and fire from lower.
Huh.
Wait a minute.
Potentially spawns piss item?
I'm not sure.
Because that's very random the way that just sort of appeared there out of nowhere, no?
That feels weird.
Insane.
So, I'm actually going to charge up here.
So, watch.
Maximum attack speed.
Ah, it's too risky.
We gotta switch.
Dude, I don't know how to do this.
How?
Just go like that or...
Oh my god.
Ho ho ho.
I'm pretty fast.
Scary.
What's that?
Sagittarius.
Peers and tears!
Now, let's not, you know, get that mixed up with spectral tears.
This is the one that goes through enemies, not obstacles.
We got point CP.
Um...
I think I'm done here.
Yeah.
Don't even want to go to the shop.
I'm happy.
Could take a key.
But nah.
And got money anyway for the shop.
So, we are gonna...
Okay, where do I go?
Okay, so the plan is...
I want to try...
to get to the strange door, right?
I know where it is...
Oh wait, I don't actually know where it is.
Yes, I do.
It is...
on the floor...
where you can't go back from the boss, right?
The red floor, uterus.
So, we're just gonna go...
the safe path.
Not the danger zone.
Yes.
Here.
Oh, not these guys.
Like, these guys have started to appear lately.
Man, my range is actually bad.
Like, pretty bad.
Thanks.
I need a buffer.
Let me charge up here.
Plus five is the max, it seems.
I don't want to use my key here.
Holy shit.
Beautiful.
Full health.
Dead end.
Thank you.
I feel like my...
piercing tears are not that useful when I don't have a lot of range.
Like, what's the point?
So, that needs to be the priority to find range right now.
Range and damage.
Mainly.
Dude, how am I so fast, though?
Not bad?
Fuck you, man.
I really thought I was oppressing their attack when you keep attacking them.
The guy in the bottom right, I kept attacking for, like, five seconds and he didn't do anything to me.
Yay!
Okay, we've gotten pretty lucky with pills, though.
That's some good luck.
Lock is turning, finally.
Oh, I stepped in the creep!
Massive blunder.
Can we get lucky again?
Hey, hey, wow.
Dude, I like it.
The fallen.
I'm gonna keep my upwards attack.
Whoa.
Wow.
Nice.
I almost died.
This is the little fucking model that my character was last run, where I couldn't see where my character was.
Why am I being reminded of that right now?
I don't want that.
I also have no HP.
Shit.
We need to play this so safe.
I think this is gonna go bad.
Obed!
Come on.
HP me.
I think I'm gonna die in a second here.
I'm probably gonna try challenges after this.
I feel like doing challenges.
What's that?
No, I don't want that.
I'm so dead here.
Dude, wait.
Oh my god.
Ho ho ho ho.
No!
No more actives.
I'd rather have this, honestly.
No, you know what?
Yeah.
I don't mind some actives, actually, if they're good, you know?
Oh, this is my end.
Yeah.
Take me out of my misery.
And let me do some challenges instead.
Not having any good times in the normal modes today.
This one was called Slow Roll.
Uh, wow.
Hundred damage?!
Wow!
Guys, this is gonna be easy.
Are you fucking kidding me?
I don't care how slow I shoot.
This is going to be a piece of cake.
Ha ha ha!
And I call this a challenge.
A challenge!
Oh, it's not Spectral.
Did he just dodge that tier?
That's crazy.
Ha ha ha!
Hundred damage?!
Oh, shit.
Uh, you're all coming...
Oh, you split up, huh?
Bananana!
This is gonna be fun, man.
I already love this challenge.
I don't love that it takes two hits to destroy these poops, though.
That's kind of annoying.
So I guess that means these poops have more than a hundred HP, right?
That's how that works.
I'm gonna say they have a hundred and one HP.
Whoa.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ah, that's awesome.
That is amazing.
That was so freaking satisfying.
Look at his HP!
Like, I'm telling you, this is going to be so easy.
Plus one lock, why not?
Gympie?
That's a nice one.
This thing again.
I'll take this.
Thanks.
Coin me.
Okay.
Very good.
I'm not done with this floor, though.
And listen up, this is why.
We are currently on the first floor.
It's a double trouble floor.
Where we don't have a... Oh, wait a minute.
We do have Angel thing.
We just went in there.
So wait, I wonder if that means...
If this is double trouble, does this actually count for two floors, then?
It's not just one bigger floor.
This is like the first and second floor combined.
Because it's only on the second floor where the Angel stuff comes in, you know?
Come here.
Oh, he walked into the...
Okay.
I mean, that's...
You do you.
I'm not going to destroy these.
It's going to take too long.
I don't roll like that right now.
I want action with this big-ass shot here.
Also, what facilitates such a big shot?
Is it this one?
Polyphemous.
Massively increases tear damage and decreases fire rate.
Tears that drop or destroy an enemy continue traveling on.
That's got to be it, huh?
All right.
Being able to angle the shot is going to be important in this one.
Now, let's not forget, there's no...
There's no treasure rooms in this game mode.
So let's not even look for that.
I could actually go into the curse room, though.
I have four hearts, right?
Seems like a good idea.
Well, let's wait a bit.
Oh, it doesn't...
Oh, if I get spectral tears, yo, that would be the massive one, right?
The way it orbits it comes around.
It's funny.
Yeah!
Oh, wrong button.
Wow.
I mean, at some point, I'm not going to be able to one-shot these anymore, I don't think.
The hell is that?
Hot soup or something?
Ooh.
I am not going to be able to afford that.
I could buy the blue heart, but then I really don't want to go into the curse room.
Three dollar playing card.
I could also do that.
No, I'm gonna...
Hmm.
I could try to go into the curse room and hope that I find twelve coins.
I know, sounds insane.
Or science, maybe.
Or I grab the blue heart and I have two buffers for the next floor.
Ooh, let's do this.
That's not a good start.
Alright.
Didn't do anything, I guess.
Whoa!
Hey, Gippy!
It was worth it.
Now we buy the other one so we have an ultimate buffer.
There it is.
You know what, fuck it, let's take the card as well.
Two of hearts, okay.
Not fantastic.
Maybe I look for a secret room as well.
Could be right here.
It's so centralized, it borders multiple rooms like this is my kind of secret room.
It's always in the center.
Well, not always, but like centralized.
And now I'm ready to leave.
Take me.
Flooded caves.
Oh.
His chance of finding a pill.
Yeah, I like it.
Yeah, let's do this as well.
Dude, I love... I just want to...
I want a character that just has this for default when you start it.
That'll be amazing.
Just one big shot, you know?
It is so satisfying.
Dude, I'm threading the needle with this.
There we go.
More?
No more.
Oh, he's massive.
Why?
Why are you so big?
Step room.
Nah, not in the challenge.
Oh, he didn't die from that.
Take... Oh, no, it's not coming off.
But it's actually not bad.
I do enjoy the take.
That was a misclick.
Takes are kind of cool.
Oh, satisfying.
That was cool.
I'm not going to walk into the other one.
16 coins.
There is one plus one equals factorial.
Humbling bundle.
Chance for pennies, bombs, keys, and red hearts to be doubled.
I mean, yeah.
That's going to pay off later.
I didn't hit it.
Beautiful.
Oh, it's perfectly aligned as well.
Double keys.
I foresee there's being a problem in a room with a lot of small enemies, though.
Unless I get a very nice shot in.
But so far, I'm loving this challenge.
Like this, for example, could be a little questionable at times.
We're going to smack him.
Nice.
Three hits.
Three hits, that's all it took.
Soulheart and Sizedown.
I mean, Sizedown is good, but it's also terrible.
Because you can't see your freaking character after a while.
Are you going to come out here?
What's that?
Lost Quirk.
A lump of coal.
Wait, isn't that going to make this even crazier?
Makes tears increase in damage and size the farther they travel.
I wonder how that scales with this setup I have going here.
Oh, no, I have no bombs.
No, I can't get it.
Aww, gee, it's well over.
That's fine.
We don't really need it.
Catacombs.
I honestly feel like I can just rush the boss right now and just murder him.
Let's actually do that.
Haha.
Oh, that's so satisfying.
I have a poop triangle now as a shot.
Oh, I got...
lost a heart there.
Throwing away some HP for no reason.
Here we go.
Carrion Queen.
What is that?
Oh, my God.
I thought we were done because the item spawned.
Plus five.
Honestly, that is... how fast am I shooting now?
It's not that much faster.
Oh, wait, that's the range.
Oh, that's nice, actually.
I like it.
Twenty-two coins, we need to go to the shop.
Let's see here.
Ladder.
Habits.
It's britches, I mean.
Why not?
Let's try it.
So...
Oh!
I thought it was an active that I had to use.
That's kind of dope.
So, I guess it can only cross one gaps.
Small gaps, it says.
I probably can't just go to the other side of the room if there's, like, three gaps of empty air.
Ladder doesn't extend that far.
It's not like I'm Norman Reedus here, you know?
Easy.
Oh, there's more.
It's kind of nice knowing whoever I shoot is just gonna die.
I can shoot my shot and think, okay, he's dead now, move on, you know?
Oh, whoa, whoa.
Don't think I want to go in there.
We have a very good devil chance right now.
I want to maintain it.
This has to be, like, the easiest challenge so far.
Like, just from the get-go, I was like, this is gonna be easy, and it is.
Now, this room, though, is one of the few that could be problematic, right?
But not really.
We handled that.
Point!
Like, just knowing that he's gonna die immediately is...
What a feeling.
Okay.
I'm fine with that.
Dude, I think we even have a good pace here.
We could do speedrun.
Just for the heck of it, you know?
Adversary.
Okay, there you are.
Not too shabby.
More health?
Nice.
No demon, though, even though we had such a big chance.
That's unlucky.
Beom, beom, beom, beom, beom!
We're ahead of the timer.
Ahoy!
Oh, the fact that it keeps going afterwards is massive for these guys.
Blister, tears have increased knockback?
I need to get my tick away, though.
Getting rich.
Just in time for the bank.
Why am I getting so much money?
There's not going to be any more shops, though.
This is unfortunate.
I need a beggar or something.
Or an arcade.
That would make me happy, too.
Solid.
I want a permanent character that does this.
That would be incredible.
I love this too much.
The fact that I can walk over here with the ladder is funny.
Mom!
I've got big triangles for you.
It's a tough one.
Okay, okay.
Hold on.
I'm going to go in here first.
I want to see this.
Grants a stacking damage bonus for each successive shot that hits an enemy.
Whoa!
Two X damage on this one?
Isn't that going to be nuts?
Ha ha ha!
I mean, let's see if it actually works.
It still says 100 damage.
There may be a cap on damage, actually.
I don't know if that's the case.
But look at the way the projectile is all red now.
Oh, you bastard!
Okay.
The thing is, though, even if I beat this...
I'm actually curious, maybe there is a way to continue on from the challenge to the next floor, you know?
That would be a great secret.
I can see that being a thing.
Like an achievement that says, haven't had enough, you know?
Or something like that.
Oops.
The little stragglers like that are going to be annoying with this.
What are you doing?
Doing that.
I think I wasted the item, actually.
Oh, shit.
Yep.
If I walk a little bit and shoot, I'm going to get that extra range, you know?
Speed.
It's valuable.
I do wonder if we can get too hush with this.
Even with a challenge.
Like, I'm like 50-50 on that.
Oh, man.
No!
This is the one...
Don't I have the...
Yeah, Gimpy.
I feel like I'm not getting any blue hearts here.
I feel scammed a little bit.
Where are you?
There you are.
You're still flying across the screen.
There you go.
Anyone else?
You.
Yeah, my damage is falling off here.
I mean, it's still good, but...
It's not that good anymore.
Ah, never mind.
It's actually pretty damn good.
I've gotten too used to one-shotting everything in the path to this place.
The good news is we have a lot of red hearts scattered all over.
Wow, that was nice.
Good.
You're gonna die now.
13 out of 15.
Ooh!
I think it's safe.
15.
Where are you?
Get that out of here.
Boom!
Now the question is... what, 22 minutes?
Nothing in here.
Let's see if anything's changed.
Doesn't look like it.
We may just have to take this, but who knows?
Maybe this will have unlocked something.
Swallow penny.
Or shallow penny.
I didn't quite read that.
I wanna do greed.
Dude, a minus four win streak is crazy.
This game is getting so much harder, much faster than I'm getting better at it, you know?
Who have we not played very much?
I feel like Kane, we haven't played Kane very much.
Or Magdalene, these two are like...
the overlooked ones.
Actually, I think as well.
I don't like Bethany very much.
Apollyon though, ooh!
Apollyon in greed mode sounds like a lot of fun.
Let's do that.
Being able to use this on items?
Dude!
Wait, can I actually just...
Wait, re-rolls each item currently held?
Ooh, I don't wanna consume that.
Yikes, I don't think that's a good idea.
We may have to re-roll, if anything.
Okay.
Let's go down here first, of course.
See, this is a classic shitty item.
Boom.
Nice!
Luck and range.
Much better.
Can I explode?
These little assholes.
Pull!
Kill him fast!
Dude, solid so far!
Okay.
That's scary.
Play it safe, and then we kill these guys.
Whoa!
Oh my god.
I think these guys just killed their friends.
With the bombs?
Because I sure didn't kill everyone.
Yeah, I can't do it.
I don't wanna consume this.
Ah, but then again, wait a minute.
Ah, it could be different in greed mode.
I was about to say, in the normal mode, it didn't actually work in the shop, right?
But maybe here it does.
Because it's, like, not quite the same.
It's a little different.
Oh, gimme that.
Two hearts only.
It's kinda...
Box, sponsor, one, red heart, key, bomb, coin, pill...
Ooh, actually!
Trinket.
Key is good, bomb is good.
Pill is maybe good.
I want it.
So that doubles I6 red hearts.
Bomb.
Rainbow worm.
Oh, oh, wait, this is the good one.
Yeah, I thought it was the one that made it spiral.
More like this.
Nice, tears up as well.
Gimme that, so now we can go in here.
Jacob's ladder!
Yeah!
Fuck yeah!
That's what I needed, baby.
We can grab this as well.
And then next up, I think I'm gonna save for whatever this is.
This soup.
Wait, why is my...
Oh no!
My trinket does kinda make my stuff go spiral sometimes.
Maybe that's rare.
Not always.
There.
Oh my god!
What the hell?
That's a crazy move you got there, sir.
Dude, I hate this trinket.
Get it off of me.
It sucks ass.
Gimme this though.
It's gonna take a while for me to kill this boss.
Wow.
Oh god.
Perhaps I can utilize his bombs against him somehow.
Ah, kill his low die.
This is the weirdest boss.
Oh god.
Fuckin' hell!
I'm gonna die.
Not like this.
Survive!
Focus!
Come on!
Oh god.
Oh man.
Oh!
Kill him!
Oh man, what the fuck.
That was so tough.
Oh wait, we have two of hearts.
Oh, doubles Isaac's red hearts, so it's gonna be...
one heal, right?
Oh, what?
Half a heal?
Man.
Let's try this.
It's probably gonna be like a healing.
No!
It's an active.
Consumes that currently held trinket and grants its effect as a permanent passive.
Oh, that sounds horrible.
For my current trinket.
Slightly increases the chance of finding trinkets as room clear rewards.
I think not.
But maybe I can use...
Ah, but do I wanna do that?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, it didn't affect these either.
Okay, so here's the deal.
We're gonna...
Just try not to die now, because we are in deep shit.
Yeah.
This is gonna be rough.
Okay, here they come.
Okay, now we should not take damage from this.
Oh, you bastard!
I can't... I'm too shit for this game, man.
I swear to God.
I cannot... The game is just too difficult for me, guys.
I just can't win.
It's crazy.
Let's do Eden.
I don't wanna play Greed.
Normal is way more fun.
Let's see here.
This is the one that spawns with different items.
Duplicates all pickups and item pedestals in the room.
Single use.
Chance of pennies, bombs, keys, and red hearts to be double.
Okay, and then we have a pill.
Sick.
All right.
Very low attack speed, though.
That is terrible.
This is gonna be a tough one.
Hey, there we go.
Attack speed fixed.
What is that?
Fire tears with many randomized effects.
God, I hate the random tear shit.
Get rainbows out of my face, you know.
But I guess the familiar is good.
I feel like just all these randomized tear effect items are...
It's not a net positive, you know.
One coin, I'm not even gonna go in.
No reason to go shopping with no money.
It's gonna make me sad looking at all the things I can't purchase.
Same goes for real life.
Famine.
Wait, I just realized I don't have any red hearts.
Oh, run is over.
Great.
If I don't get a red heart now...
Okay.
Well, that just sucks.
That's just random.
Didn't get any red hearts.
Eve.
That's the whore.
I'm just gonna bang my head against the wall until the wall breaks.
This is now the battle plan.
And you know what?
It's actually good that we take damage on her...
because we want to be at 1 HP.
That was a little bit risky what I did there.
Hey, speed run?
This was a fast boss.
Oish.
Don't do it.
Actually, don't mind that he's jumping.
It's predictable.
That was good.
Clean.
Like, I feel like I'm just getting...
So there's like apparently a million items in this game, right?
But it feels like I'm only getting 30.
Well, you know, at all times.
I'm seeing the same items again and again and again and again.
There's like...
It doesn't feel like there's that many items even though I've unlocked a shit-ton.
I'll get the same item like three times in a row, you know?
On three different characters and this was great.
Now we're at 1 HP permanently.
Maybe a blessing in disguise on this character.
Who knows?
We now got good speed and health.
Or not health but damage.
Now we need some buffers.
What's that?
Causes all spikes and obstacles.
Yo!
That's big for me with 1 HP.
Very nice.
Nothing I want in here.
Maybe the compass.
And maybe a key.
Yeah, much better damage.
And a knife.
Let's do this one too.
The plan is still the same.
To get to the strange door.
That's been like my main goal today.
Throughout all of these runs.
Except the Greek ones of course.
The thing is though, like I can't even make it to floor 5 before I die, you know?
This is the problem right now.
What is that?
Bloody crown.
A treasure room will appear in the womb and corpse floors.
How about we get there first, huh?
Let's not think about that right now.
Oh my god, bro.
How is he one-shotting me anyway?
I was at one heart.
Does he do a full heart of damage or what suddenly?
I feel like I've just hit a wall in this game, guys.
I just can't win anymore.
Maybe with a sizzle?
I don't know.
Game is too fucking hard for me.
Treasure room off the bed.
Wow!
I'm telling you, as soon as you roll a sizzle, you win the game.
It makes no sense to play any other characters.
Why would you?
Legitimately have no idea how I just took damage.
I didn't see any projectiles, I didn't see nothing.
No idea what just happened.
But okay, maybe one of the worms appeared right underneath my feet.
That could have been it, but not sure.
I think this one will be good to get.
Could also...
Nah.
Three dollar pill.
Oh, he exploded!
Not ready for that.
Got me good.
Think those up.
You're not gonna explode, are you?
Okay.
Second hand, increase the duration of status effects.
Uh, hey guys, don't mind me.
I gotta kill this.
Okay, so let's see.
Treasure room has been found.
Wait, how come this isn't explored?
Look at the room between us here.
Huh?
Did I get teleported?
What happened?
Wait, what actually happened?
Huh.
Oh, it's probably the curse we have.
Yeah, that's it.
Whoa.
Uh, see, I would say maybe we could re-roll this, but this is actually good.
I need that.
And...
I don't care about these rooms here, I'm gonna go straight for...
For the strange door.
Oh, shit!
Okay, dude.
That's cool.
Love that.
Thank you.
This guy wants bombs, and you know what?
Fine.
Give me HP.
Come on.
Take everything.
Oh, take everything I own, actually.
Here, here's some more bombs for you.
Make my day.
Come on, punk.
Alright, fine.
Be that way.
These guys explode, I think.
Gotta be makin' careful.
Nope, okay.
Oh, my God.
Soulheart's massive.
Um, we have the fool.
So we use the fool.
I had trouble getting that out.
Uh, acid baby.
Drops a pill every seven rooms.
I don't like this.
I'm gonna re-roll.
You see what I mean?
I'm getting the same items.
It's like there's a higher chance of getting the same item that you had on the last run than you do on this run.
Like, it doesn't feel like the RNG is equal.
There's some hidden modifiers, I think.
A pill!
Eh.
Nothin'.
Nothin' interesting there.
No, don't...
Oh, I wasted all my flies.
Ten gold.
One key.
You know what?
Let's go into puberty.
I like it.
I may actually buy this key.
Because I can see myself going to the next floor, not having a key, and I see a treasure room.
And I'm gonna hate it.
Ooh, that's nice!
I like it!
I'm not gonna...
Oh, I can't even re-roll it anyway.
Even if I wanted to, but that's fine.
Um...
You know what?
You may say sunken cost fallacy.
I say you're wrong.
We're going up here and we're giving this guy all our bombs.
Surely we'll get something now.
Come on now!
Eeee, okay.
I mean, okay, alright.
There was a chance we could've gotten something good, right?
And since we're on Azazel, chances were pretty high.
Too spooky!
That's good!
I like this one a lot.
This is a good item.
We're taking it.
Hells yeah.
Now, do we go to the crazy area?
Um...
I'm trying to think right now.
If...
That strange door had anything to do with those areas.
I remember that we found this knife, right?
But that didn't have anything to do with that.
So I think it's actually fine if we go down.
The fleshy door and stuff.
That's not related to this, I don't think.
That's different.
Um...
Okay.
This way.
Oh, this soundtrack is some of the best in the game.
A lot of caves.
Reminds me of the Terran theme from Starcraft 2 a little bit.
Oh god.
Play safe.
This guy's gonna explode, I think.
There are so many enemies.
What the hell?
Isn't this a lot?
D6 is ready.
Don't even think about taking my...
Oi, oi, oi.
Who's gonna take my charge?
No treasure room yet.
I may actually save the D6 for the Devil Room.
But then again, we only have one red heart.
I'm not sure about that.
Oh shit.
Oh my god, no!
Just lost a full heart!
You know what?
Go!
We gotta go now.
Hey, look at his face!
That's how we determine where he's gonna shoot.
Oh, thank god!
Ah, no demon though, no demon.
Range is good though.
We love Rainshaw on his Hazel.
Uh, should I go in there?
Nah, probably not, right?
Treasure room time.
Scary.
Okay.
Giant cell.
Let's see, taking damage spawns on mini- I don't like this one very much.
Reroll.
Metal plate.
Chance to reflect enemy projectiles.
That's good!
That's survival.
And we needed that extra HP right now.
Okay.
Are we done here?
I think we're done.
Then again, ah, no, no, no.
We're not gonna go in there.
Save the key.
Let's do...
No.
No, no, no.
That place is scary as hell.
Right now it's all about just getting to the endgame.
Because that in itself is, for some reason, insanely difficult nowadays.
Like just surviving these first five floors.
We do have help from above if we need it.
Yes.
A pill.
Experimental pill.
That's bad for me.
Alright, we're gonna do this again.
Trust.
I need HP.
Give me like an HP upgrade.
I mean, money's cool too.
Alright, 15 is nice.
Ready for the shop, if need be.
Oh, what was that?
That battery?
That sort of battery.
Could be nice for me with the D6.
Let me see what that was.
I think it's the one that charges one bar automatically or something.
The final charge.
Okay, it's not that great.
But the secondhand timer is not really doing anything for me.
A lot of pills.
Nah.
What is that?
Hemolacria.
Less tears, more damage, less range?
Replaces tears with large arcing bloodshots that burst into a spray of smaller bloodshots on impact.
Large shots deal increased damage, whatever reduced fire rate.
I'm not sure if this is actually good for me.
It says it replaces tears.
Isn't this the one I took on that one run that turned into like pure shit?
And then I had to use a reroll to get everything back to something workable?
Fuck this noise, man.
Maybe I'll come back.
Depends whether or not I find more charges on my battery.
What's in here?
Wait, we had a shop.
But no key, I guess.
Yeah, this is the problem.
What's going on here?
What is this weird room?
Oh, there you are.
I need battery.
Oh, no way!
I can't believe that.
Oi, oi, oi.
Not looking good.
Boss time?
Maybe a good idea.
No, I need some charges first.
Just in case I get a really shitty reward, you know, and I want to reroll it.
Holy shit!
Oish!
Ah!
I'm fighting for my life here.
Battery?
Okay, here we go.
Let's do this.
Gertie.
Man, that jump, it may actually kill me.
Oi, oi, oi.
Shit.
Thank God he died.
If there's health, I take it.
I'm gonna take it?
No, no.
Oh, man, this is...
I think I'm gonna take this, because it's just too good.
And then we're gonna go back and reroll the other thing and hope for something...
Jesus juice is solid, you know?
But then we take that, and then we go back now and reroll the other item.
Let's go through here.
Ah, where was it?
Back there.
Okay, here.
Come on!
All right!
I mean, more money?
I'm looking for that HP, though, son.
Can you make it happen or not?
Hey, that's good!
Pills galore.
Sous-soul hearts.
Yes!
Oh, okay.
I thought they would drop on the ground, and then I had to pick them up, but this works as well.
And now we can get in here with all the money.
Let's see.
Grants one bar of charge to the active item for every 15 enemies killed.
Yo, that's really good!
Playing card.
Two soul hearts!
Yo, we can buy that?
This... oh, we cannot buy this as well, but recharges one bar of Isaac's active item each time he takes damage is also good.
Dude, all of these are, like, made...
Oh, dude, I can take this and this, and I'm gonna have charges for years.
Imagine.
Uh, maybe we can even go find some more money?
Dude, we have an arcade.
We're gonna make money.
We're gonna be able to afford all three.
All three, baby!
I can also give him red hearts.
Yeah, actually, that's a good idea.
I need one more coin.
That's it!
That's actually all I need.
Now we can go up here and heal.
Give me that.
We can actually get more money as well.
Uh, leave that there, also.
Oh.
Uh, up here.
This shop is crazy, by the way.
It's a really good shop.
I'm taking this.
And this.
Oh, yeah, we got a buffer now.
Very nice.
I'm gonna take a bit more money here.
Give
me that.
And now we move on.
I'm done.
Ah, no bombs.
We have to keep in mind, though, I gotta find something that will allow me to either rewind, time, or teleport out of the room.
Something like it, you know?
We're gonna need this later.
Oh, shit.
Oh, close one.
Yes.
Whoa.
These rooms are fine, like...
Ah, fuck.
I say that too early.
Normally, though, these rooms are fine.
There's nothing that can happen to me.
Full charge already.
Show me a treasure room, then.
Okay, we got a shop.
Let me just hide in here.
Heh heh.
Mom's key.
Perhaps if I get the money.
Wait, no effect.
Hold on a minute.
Okay, I was about to say, shouldn't that converge that pill into something better?
But it's only the bad ones.
I guess this one can be considered neutral.
Playing it safe.
The fool.
Teleporter.
Yay!
I actually need that.
We're gonna come back for that.
Where's my treasure room, dammit?
Like, I'm wasting all these rooms here on charge that I can't use.
Okay, let's just do the Boston.
Maybe re-roll that.
That's for you!
Oh, no.
Bastard!
Oh,
god.
Calm down, dude.
Oh, I reflected that shot, you saw that?
That saved me a little bit.
Nice, breakfast is huge.
Definitely taking that.
Ahh!
Repreem!
Again, a sasle common double use.
Can't go wrong with a sasle, man.
Every time.
What is that, though?
It looks like one of those shitty worms that make me shoot spirals, so I'm already gonna say no to that.
I'm taking this, even though no more red hearts, don't care.
It's too strong.
We either die with this, or succeed.
Let's just not take damage in a stupid way, you know?
Like, that could have been a really stupid way to take damage.
Defeated angels will drop angel room items instead of key pieces.
Ha!
If a key piece was previously collected, angels will spawn the other key piece before producing angel items.
Um...
Well, we're not going stepping anytime soon, and we're not gonna get any angel rooms, so maybe it's not that great.
I'm gonna leave it.
Huge!
Milk!
Wait!
After ten hits, the glass breaks.
I think I wanna re-roll that.
Ooh, what's that?
That's key!
Opens all doors!
Oh, wait, it's an active!
Oh my god!
Opens all closed doors in the current room.
Bypasses locks and most doors with special requirements.
Dude!
Wait a minute, I can't leave this behind, I need a backpack!
Is there anything else I wanna re-roll?
I may wanna keep this?
Any special requirements?
I guess that should work on... what's it called?
The fucking... the strange door!
I'm taking a gamble here, guys.
I have a good feeling about this.
Unless the game lies to me like it sometimes does.
Um...
What's that?
Oh, key.
Okay.
Don't take damage now in some stupid way.
Oh!
The reflection!
Saved my ass just now.
Wow.
That was scary.
Flat file.
I don't want that.
Ewie!
Dude, stop jumping!
Uh, Mom?
Okay.
Also, this has two charges.
Almost all closed doors in the current room.
Actually insane.
I wonder if that works with...
Oh, shit!
We can open the door on command!
It's gotta be this...
Oh, man, that is actually awesome.
Uh, I'm gonna blow this up.
It was a bad idea.
Uh, we really should leave because we're gonna get a heart by leaving.
And staying is just gonna risk it, you know?
Uh, oh, we need this as well, of course, on the way back.
Actually, maybe we don't now.
But now at least I have an insurance, right?
We're gonna try a Saki.
If Saki doesn't work, we're gonna go to Mom, slap her butt, and then we're gonna use the Fool.
Uh, we can fly, so everything's cool.
Yo, thanks.
A hermit.
Ooh.
I can use this as well.
I'd rather use this.
Actually, uh, wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, that... Oh, shit!
That worked on that!
Um, I'll take this.
I thought for sure the other door would open as well, but no, I guess not.
What the hell is that?
That is a nasty boss.
Tears up is great.
Okay, so let me try again.
Dude, I took... See, the game was lying.
I fucking knew it.
I knew I, uh...
Yeah, I knew it.
I just knew it.
It did not open all the doors in the room.
You cannot trust it, man.
Goes to reason that we probably cannot open the strange door as well, or either.
But maybe.
Ooh, a dice room.
Three.
Wait!
What is that?
We don't know what it is.
We're going to take it.
Okay, so let me just double-check everything.
Uh, alright.
Keys, money, stats...
Go.
We got a key.
Nothing happened here.
No, it's the same.
Okay, I'm just going to write it down.
Oh, I already had it open.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Fuck.
I guess it wasn't open that long.
Sorry about that.
I'm just gonna add a couple more question marks.
This is gonna indicate how many times I've tried it, okay?
Let's go.
Kinda lucky that I just decided to write that there.
I will say, though, I feel like my damage is not that great.
At this point, usually, you know, I have insane damage, not just good damage.
Ooh!
Holy buffer!
Don't mind if I do.
Oh my god!
More options is good, but I come back with more money.
Boss acquired.
Oh, that was a spiky rock.
I think we go.
Uh... I gotta focus here.
Just focus.
I'm afraid of that foot.
Okay, good dodge.
Double trouble there.
Nice.
Okay, okay.
So check it out.
Can be used to open a strange door.
But this one, like... So this one allows access to deeper stages.
This one allows access to higher stages.
I'll take the negative.
Thank you.
They both open a strange door, apparently.
Let's see.
Oh,
so wait, the door here was the strange door?
I thought that was a different door.
Where's the main room?
Did I come in over here?
I must have.
Ooh, is it gonna work?
Yes!
Oh.
Just takes me to the mausoleum?
Oh, shit, well... Alright.
I guess that's... whatever.
Fine.
Mausoleum 2.
Oh, wait, did that say mausoleum 3?
Is that the gimmick?
I didn't quite get that.
Well, I'm kind of sad now because I really didn't want to go down here yet.
I was just kind of, you know, excited.
So I just jumped down.
What?
Oh, that probably would have killed everyone in here.
Whoops.
Oh, okay.
I guess I can just circumvent all these mechanics because I can fly.
Actually, hold on.
This guy wants hearts.
There you go, buddy.
One more.
Fuck you, then.
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
We got another heart.
There.
Come on, give me something good.
Bible-tracked.
Okay.
Here.
I'm gonna come back for you.
We're gonna do great things together.
Oh, look.
Dora's been open, baby.
And soul hearts as well.
We love that.
Oh, God.
Oh.
This guy's dangerous.
Oh, my God.
That's so difficult to dodge.
Where are you?
Oh, you're dead.
Okay.
Hey, um, calm down, lady.
I'm not gonna fall for your song.
Do you think I am a sailor or something?
Wait, was I missing all those shots?
I think I was.
Ooh, interesting.
But I don't have more hearts.
Not yet.
Can I?
Ah, I can't.
But I can blow it up.
Wait, I wonder, does my key also work on these things?
No, it's only doors.
Bypasses, locks, and most doors.
Okay, fuck you, then.
It said most doors.
Ah, I'll give it to you, game.
You did say most.
I grant you that one.
Fine.
Uh, not worth it to open that to get a key, honestly.
Ooh!
Planetarium!
What's that?
Your anus.
There's ice tears in there.
Slows enemies.
Enemies killed by ice tears become frozen solid.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, we know that.
Very nice.
Also, I'm joking, guys.
I know it's called Uranus.
I'm just immature and, you know...
Best friend, places of decoy.
No thanks!
I want question mark.
Obsessed fan.
Fly familiar that follows Isaac's movements on a delay, deals contact damage.
Ha!
Okay.
I could try and get some blue hearts here.
But let's save that.
Yo!
That's good.
Oh, everyone got frozen!
Oh my god, this is actually kind of huge on Azazel.
Chances of getting frozen is like massive with this.
It may even be guaranteed.
Ha ha, they're all frozen.
Oh my god.
It's not guaranteed.
So satisfying to break people.
Ah, I don't want anything here.
Booster pack.
And again, I don't have any cards right now.
And am I really going to have anything to spend my money on?
Fuck, let's do it.
Is that a credit card?
Makes any purchasable items and pickups in the current world free!
Credit card.
Hey, that's cool.
Chariots.
And another chariot.
Two of diamonds.
Doubles coins.
Teleport to the starting room.
Some coins.
I don't know what I want.
Maybe a chariot.
Could be nice, I guess, as a panic button, you know?
Dude, if you just get the enemies frozen, you don't need to kill them anymore.
It's like super nice.
Oh no!
It's almost like a chance to instakill, is what this is.
If you think about it.
Wait, what?
That's note!
That's spend everything!
Wait, dude, we have a...
My pass is locked in most doors.
Dude, it's all about death!
He spent all the savings, mom was met.
Wait, what is this even?
It's that mausoleum too, but...
I'm not sure what's happening here.
More tears?
Yes!
Absolutely.
Yo, this looks crazy.
Uh, what is this treasure room?
That ain't a treasure room I know of.
Oh, really?
I can't get in there and destroy them then.
Dude, the music, oh.
Uh, are we about to ascend?
Wait, depth two?
Wait, are we actually getting out?
We're not going deeper, we're going higher!
Uh, hello?
Get out of here!
I need to... I need to not be as fast...
Oh my god, we can...
Okay.
Depth one!
Maggie!
Uh, I don't know who's... the bad... I mean, mom is obviously the bad guy, but...
Maybe dad was also a bad guy?
He definitely went to get milk, it seems.
Which ain't good, you know?
That means it's not good.
He spent all the savings, I mean, that's bad, right?
But is it really, like, that bad?
Maybe not that bad.
Oh my god!
I got... bamboozled!
We don't have a lot of HP here!
Mom's foot stomps down, that's not... no, I want this instead.
Higher!
Go!
Caves two!
Hopefully it's gonna get easier as well when we go up.
What the hell is that thing?
Look at this!
That's a new type of enemy!
And it has a lot of HP!
Things are not getting easier.
Almost got hit there.
Dude, where's my item's ass?
No!
Bastard hit me!
I'm in trouble here.
Uh...
I'm not an adult yet, man, fuck.
Oh, shit.
We go up!
Yeah.
Man, Mom is a nut job!
I should have gone with Dad when he left!
Oh my god, oh, that's huge actually.
Give me more blue hearts, yes please.
Oh, this thing with a million HP.
Man, this thing is no joke.
Still no treasures in these.
I think it's because we already took the treasures in these floors.
I wonder if we hadn't taken the treasure, if they would have been here now.
Oh no, this one's gonna... it's maybe a little problematic.
Oh, but the fact that they freeze though means they can't explode into little tiny guys.
Look at that massive fly.
It's disgusting.
Here we go.
Pick me up!
Basement 2!
Dude, the HP on this guy is insane!
What the hell?
I probably should have destroyed those actually.
Come on.
Dude, some of these guys just can't die.
Oh crap.
Freeze him!
You're under arrest.
Oh, he's charmed, that's nice.
Oh god.
Yes, yes, yes, good.
Oh, wait.
Basement 1!
Oh my god, dead!
Dead, I miss you!
How would you do this to me?
Man.
He knew he left me with a fucking nutjob for a mother too.
Maybe it's dad who put up the poster.
Yeah, Eternal Heart is kinda nuts.
Uh, okay, we go.
Oh my god.
Torn photo.
What the hell?
Yo, there's gonna be a boss here at the end.
For sure.
Yo, look, it's like a hallway.
We got pictures on the wall and shit.
Dude, what?
Wait, dude, we're exploring our home for the first time.
We get to leave our room.
That's crazy.
Dude, I wonder.
That's key.
I wonder if that opens something in dad's room, if we have a dad's room.
Right?
That's like a storage area or like a closet thing.
So wait, back here we have...
Is this my room then?
It must be, right?
Let me blow up the bed as well.
We're never gonna come back to this place.
Wait, there's a small drawing underneath.
Look.
We probably did that.
Dude, this is exciting.
Oh my god, it's where mom was watching TV!
Turn on the TV.
Let's watch Christian broadcasts.
Blow it up.
Leave it from behind.
Oh no, wait, that's not allowed in religion.
Wait, I can't...
Let me blow up the couch.
Okay,
I'm wasting a lot of bombs here.
Which may not be a good idea.
This is mom's room.
Oh, mom's lipstick?
The Bible.
The red key has appeared in the basement.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, what?
Opens nearby doors to mysterious, hidden, red roofs.
While held, the outlines of these hidden doors can be seen on certain walls.
Ha!
Wait, while held, the outlines of these hidden doors can be seen on certain walls.
Really?
In here?
Oh.
What happened?
Christian broadcasts?
Oh shit.
Uh-oh, wait, imagine mom is home now.
What if she went shopping and now she's home?
Oh shit.
I'm scared.
I'm so scared.
Wait, we can go back here.
That feels kind of buggy, doesn't it?
I know I have four bombs.
I'm gonna try and blow some stuff up here.
Wait, I got two bombs left.
One more here, and then...
Oh my god.
It's like outlines.
Ooh, no, Mom is home!
He's watching TV!
Wait a minute, before I go in there, I need to investigate this room more.
So, wait a minute.
While held, the outlines of these hidden doors can be seen or in certain walls.
I can't see shit, though.
Unless I'm blind.
I can't see anything.
Maybe here?
Oh, there.
There's an outline there!
How do I get in?
Am I crazy?
Look!
I don't know if you can see that.
There's a red outline there.
Oh, wait, it's an active.
Oh!
A sasal?
I already have a sasal.
I'm so confused right now.
Well, whoever it was was locked in here for a long time.
Yo, look at the minimap, a red room.
Last bomb, we're gonna use it.
Fuck.
Okay.
So, I guess I just got to keep looking for these outlines.
To find secrets.
Wait, let me go back.
Now that I know what it looks like.
No, I don't see anything here.
Dude, we're about to have a boss fight, I think, and it's gonna be against...
Mom, big surprise.
Get ready.
Or not.
Whoa!
Dogma!
What?!
Oh, we gotta destroy the TV!
TV, TV, TV, TV, TV, TV!
Oh, god.
We got static!
Yo, if we destroy the TV, Mom's not gonna be able to watch Christian broadcasts.
And maybe she'll be cured.
Guys, this game is saying it all.
This TV is bad for the soul, you know?
You can't be watching broadcasts.
Yo, what is happening?
There's snow on the screen.
Wow.
We're not done.
Am I hearing Dad's voice?
Dude, what the heck?
Dude, I'm dead.
I'm dead.
Oh, my god.
Dodge the shit out of this!
Oh, we're watching... it's television sounds we're hearing.
Sports broadcasts and stuff.
Oh, my god.
No, no, no, no!
Dude, that was awesome, though!
I gotta come back here.
We gotta do this immediately.
Ah, we gotta go.
Again, as Hazel.
I need as Hazel for this.
I need it.
We're going back in.
Come on.
I need to go back there immediately.
That is so freaking fucking dope, man.
I loved everything about that.
Yes, that's huge!
Dude, this is a great start.
Common as Hazel W, once again.
Just unbelievable luck, you know?
Next up, we're gonna get Bramestone again.
Watch.
We're gonna get Bramestone.
Or something even better.
Ludo.
Duke, bring it on.
I'm on a mission.
And you know what the best part is?
We have the Fool right now.
So we're actually kinda equipped for this.
From the get-go.
Uh, yep.
Gimme.
Yeah, that's huge.
I'll be taking that.
Uh, fuck it.
We go.
Huge.
So now what?
Wait, shouldn't we have... uh, wait, I'm confused.
Shouldn't we have two red hearts right now?
Can I actually not count to two?
What's happening?
Uh, I'm not sure.
I'm not sure what just happened.
Maybe the random stat was my HP?
Can that be a thing?
Maybe?
I didn't notice that if that was the case.
Must've been.
That's weird.
Uh, come here.
Okay, so we gotta be ready for the TV demon.
This guy's out here causing static, you know?
Can't let that slide.
Watching TV's bad for you.
This is the message of the game.
Don't get indoctrinated by the TV.
And everything you see on the news...
Go this way.
Makes me think of not...
I don't want to say my mom, because my mom is nothing like mom in this game, okay?
I'm just saying, like, parents in general have this idea that's...
Oh, you've been sitting in front of the computer too much today, you know?
When they've been sitting in front of the TV all day.
Like, dude, at least I'm being, like, active with my brain, you know?
The Black Bean.
Upon taking damage, Isaac releases several farts, the damage poison, pushback enemies.
I like it.
I've always hated that double standard, you know?
Oh, this one's gonna be easy, Kazama Seizel.
Gym.
Oh, dude, I'm so sad, actually.
I just realized...
I should have experimented more with the dad's key.
Dude, one of the chances I get dad's key and I go to a place where dad is speaking of all, you know, of all runs.
Fuck, I may have missed something huge.
Oh...
Also, I don't understand what it meant with, like, unlock the Seizel.
Wait, does something change on a Seizel?
Not sure.
You know what I think it is?
It's probably, like, a mini Seizel that you can find.
A familiar... Wait a minute, doesn't that already exist?
That's a thing already, isn't it?
No, that's a little brimstone.
That's a little brimstone, I'm thinking of.
Sulfur, speaking of brimstone...
You know what, I'll take it.
Nah, wait, is it worth it?
It's just for one room.
But I guess, I mean, if we're gonna play against a crazy boss, then this is good.
This is a guaranteed brimstone against a boss.
Right?
I'm taking it.
Poor man's brimstone.
Let's go.
Okay, so now...
The goal is to find a bit of HP.
Just because we are kinda low on that.
How dare you?
Okay.
I'm playing it safe here.
We're going a little slow, but still determined.
I gotta hold on to the fool as well.
Oh shit.
I'm always so scared of lasers on those guys.
Money.
What's that?
Oh, that's a good one!
I like this one.
That is actually a solid damage.
Just one shot that guy, right?
What is this?
Oh, active items.
Two charges, not really gonna be super useful for me though.
Maybe in a case where I need to kill a boss in quick succession between two rooms.
Okay, we actually have 15 now.
Yes, we'll buy it.
Okay, here we go.
The Wretched.
Thank you, daddy.
Long legs.
I'm gonna wait for him to jump.
Oi, yo, yo.
Is that...
Oh, perfectiona!
HP acquired as well.
I'm taking that.
I'm taking it.
Let's go.
I need range.
Actually, it doesn't matter.
I have the brimstone on command.
That's the way I need to think about this.
When I need it, I can always activate it in a boss room, right?
Okay, so we actually have two charges now.
Oh yeah, oh, I can actually make it more powerful.
So it is actually super good here.
Not bad.
I love the perfectiona!
I wasn't focused!
Shit!
It happens.
I got excited.
I got excited at the prospect of double laser.
And I forgot that I had perfectionism as a trait.
Nothing.
Thank you, daddy.
Hey, a buffer!
Well, another buffer.
Woah!
Ten coins.
And a pill as well.
This is gonna be, watch, it's gonna be a plus one health.
I know it in my heart.
I'll take that as well.
Poor man's perfectionista.
Wait, treasure room.
Totally abandoned the treasure room for some reason.
And shop as well, actually.
Ball of tar.
Slowing tears are good, man.
Especially when I do the brr with the laser.
It's gonna hit multiple times and have a high chance of applying it.
I got hit.
I need more tears.
Woah!
Dude, I was running from the shadow, but the shadow is daddy long legs.
Not smart.
Okay, well, we got the money now for the shop.
Exactly 15.
Ooh, fanny pack.
Drop a pickup and take damage, yeah.
Thought it was a backpack.
This will do as well.
We can look for secrets on the way.
We have 14 bombs.
I predict right in here.
Nope, never mind.
Okay, well.
Gertie.
Oi, oi, oi.
We got the pearls, range is amazing for me.
So, okay.
What's going on with this heart here?
Let's pay attention.
We're gonna try and keep that intact as much as possible.
Oh, shit.
Oh, you bastard.
What's that?
Head of Krampus.
Another brimstone active.
No, thanks.
Boo.
Don't like that.
Okay, so now we're gonna go north.
Ah, yes.
That was Isaac's red hearts.
That's not good for me.
Blow it up.
Hemetemesis.
Ha!
Wait a minute.
I didn't lose any health doing that.
Normally, when I use hematemesis, I lose health.
Maybe the little rotten thing on my heart means that it is immune to taking damage.
No, that would be too broken.
Maybe if it's covered by black hearts, it doesn't get consumed when I use a blood donation machine.
You know, that type of immunity.
I'm just totally pulling things out of my ass here.
But it could be.
Oh, no!
I ran into the only obstacle in the room that did damage, and it was static.
And it was in the center.
Good job.
Oi, oi.
Trying to steal my charges.
I'm saving that for a very certain someone.
Saving the bullet for Barbosa.
Ah, nice!
Mars!
Double tap dash?
It's a dash attack that can be activated by double tapping a move button.
I think it's immune to most damage while charging.
It deals contact damage that scales with its tear damage.
Ooh, that's a very long cooldown.
A magician?
No, I need this, though.
Like, I gotta keep that on me at all times.
Wait.
This looks a little...
Doesn't it?
Okay, I mean, if they're not gonna move.
Sure.
Ah, what is that?
Little gish.
Fire slowing tears.
More slow.
Oh,
what the fuck was that?
You saw that?
Okay, let me try this.
Blood donation.
Okay, just consumed it.
So that's not what that does, I guess.
Maybe it's like, hey, if you hold on to it for two floors, then you're gonna get two hearts or something, you know?
It's like double the risk, double the reward, something like that.
Let's do this.
War.
I could use brimstone here, but...
Ah, you know what, maybe we'll do it.
Ah, cube of meat.
I hate that.
All right, go.
Moving on.
Dank depths.
Whoa, whoa, wait, the door was there.
I thought it was when we got to the mom.
Maybe we are the mom already.
Did I underestimate how far we are?
Whoa, I didn't mean to do that.
I have to remember that I can do that.
Wait, I can probably go through, what do you call it, the spiky rooms.
The fucking curse room.
Watch.
Okay, but I was flying, so maybe that doesn't count.
Oh my god!
Hold on, take care of these first.
We got a false PhD and the black hole thingy.
Actually, not bad.
But that's all my red hearts then.
Let me see, that's one black heart, most good pill effects bad, but it's also grants permanent damage ups.
Consuming most other pill types will also spawn a black heart.
That is pretty good, but this is very nice, you know?
Give me that.
This is not great.
Hey, it worked!
Okay, sick.
Didn't take damage there.
Oh shit, sometimes I didn't mean to do it, it just doesn't.
Oh shit, I don't have brimstone anymore.
Dude!
I can't believe that.
Sure.
I guess we'll take something.
Arcade could maybe save us.
This guy wants, he's gonna give me battery I'm pretty sure.
Let's just see.
Yeah, okay, that's, I'm gonna blow these up.
Whoa!
Didn't mean to.
Aw, two red hearts.
This room again.
Hahaha, wow.
That's one way to do it.
Oh!
That was scary.
And I have two black cards.
I can't, I can't win this.
I need more.
Just not good enough.
Even if I had the red heart.
You know, it's just not good enough.
No!
Well, now we're dead, I think.
Nevermind.
Blue heart acquired.
Give me a temptation card.
The hermit, no.
Hermit, okay, so what does this do?
Sets I6 health to one red heart.
And spawns, okay, I see.
Good, I will never forget now.
You know what, let's use this anyway, because the shop is right there.
Steam sale.
Could do that.
Or a pill.
Take this and then buy a pill, I guess.
Nice!
I was hoping for health up, but this will do as well.
Sick.
Give me this.
Now, where is the boss?
Forgot about the treasure room.
Pinky eye, chance to fire poison tears.
That's actually not bad.
More damage is what I need.
This one is blowing hourglass.
Oh, okay.
No, I can't do it.
I got to keep my brimstone.
It is my one saving grace.
Got him.
Just blow it up.
It can't spawn blue hearts anyway, in my experience.
It's just red hearts, bombs, keys.
And that's pretty much it.
Mom!
I think she got slowed down there.
Oi, oi, oi!
Nice!
Yo, we were even fast?
Dude, let's do it.
This could be the saving grace.
Only if we get something good.
Dead tooth, firing creates an aura around, I say, the poison's enemies.
Tried off glass.
Chance to spawn a red heart when damaged.
No, taking damage will make Isaac.
20 seconds.
No, no, no, no, no, no, absolutely not.
Speedball, more speed, more, that's useless for me.
Mutant spider fires four tears at once, and then...
Dude, I don't even like this.
Wait.
Unless...
This actually makes me shoot four laser tears.
Oh, but the charge is bad!
Oh wait, it's not even that spread.
What the hell?
Wait, do I get the stack of Olas?
Is it 4x damage?
Oh no, I'm dead.
I want a black heart!
I can't do this.
Yeah, it's over.
One brush with anything, and I'm out.
Yo!
No, give me... give me blue hearts or something.
Wow.
Oh, what the fuck was that?
I misclicked.
Oh my god!
Oh yeah, I mean, okay.
I forgot to activate my brimstone as well, but, you know.
Chance!
God fucking damn it, man.
Honestly, I would have died anyway.
The reason I even went in there is because...
It could have been my one ticket to getting more powerful to actually be able to beat this final boss in the TV, you know?
I had to gamble it all on that.
I just had to.
I kind of want to go again.
Dude, minus nine streak makes me want to cry, man.
I can't win in this game unless I play as Azazel.
It has gotten to the point where the game is simply too fucking hard.
You know?
It's too fucking hard to play.
It's crazy.
Like, I cannot win.
Maybe with Isaac, D6 is good, I guess.
Magdalene...
I mean, Magdalene is actually... if you find damage, right?
Then you're kind of set.
Because starting with four hearts is pretty much a guarantee that you're going to get...
or that you'll be able to take devil deals.
Also, what is this... hold on, so Azazel...
I need to see my unlocks.
Items.
No, not items.
Secrets?
It said you unlocked Azazel, right?
Dude, why the fuck is it not ordered so that the latest one you got is in the front?
That is so stupid.
How is this not, like, immediately obvious to anyone who opens this game?
Like, am I crazy?
It's such a weird design decision.
Oh, let me see those stats, actually.
33 mom kills, 200 secrets!
Best streak is two!
Yikes.
490 items, I don't need to see this.
Hey, I mean...
We are actually close to having everything.
Never mind.
Whoa, okay, never mind.
They kind of look like I was close.
We're going to do one more run.
One last, just to finish it off, you know?
Let's do random.
Where's random?
Go!
Let's do it.
Samsung!
I kind of like this guy.
Three hearts, 3.5 damage.
You get more damage if you fuck up.
It's nice.
All-around W.
This room is absolutely bonkers, by the way.
What a starting room.
Okay, he's dead, at least.
Now, this guy needs to die.
I've already hit him, like, ten times.
You see, this is where the game is at right now.
I can barely beat the first room.
Of the first floor.
Like, why are they so spongy?
It's too much, man.
We can actually step here.
Oh, wait, that's not a step room.
Looked like one.
Pills.
Okay.
Nice!
Not so nice.
Okay.
I mean, all in all, I would say, successful.
That was a good gamble there.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Oh, no.
This is insanity.
Wow!
Wow, sirs.
Okay,
small guy's gone.
Trust we're gonna do it on Samson.
I have a good feeling about this run, actually.
It's not a Zazul, but, you know.
There's a shop.
Still no treasure room found.
Okay, hold on.
I can't leave yet.
There it is.
What the fuck?
Wow.
Dude, I'm kind of killing it, actually.
Okay.
Spider enemies, though.
They're not that scary anymore.
I feel like I've gotten better at it, so now this item is actually worth less to me.
In the beginning, this item was gold.
Now it's bronze.
Fuck!
Let me go in here.
More pills, maybe.
Do it.
Hemotemesis.
Oh, wait, dude, a bomb.
I'm gonna take a bomb.
We're gonna go back.
I'm gonna open this chest down here.
This is the plan.
And we also get damage, right?
Because we took damage just now.
Whoa!
Holy...
Nice!
Good chest.
Look at all the damage we're getting.
Yo, this is actually a strategy on Samson.
You take damage intentionally when you have healing lying around like this.
But it's only for one floor, I guess.
Let's go murder the boss.
We don't need more damage.
Oh, whoa.
I'm playing snake.
Flawless!
Speed is fine.
I'm trying to figure out what the best item on this guy would be.
Something that would do self-harm, not like the razor, right?
Like, that would be super good.
We have the curse of, I think, confusion, that is.
That's gonna be annoying.
Oh, shit.
I think my fly just absorbed that one shot.
Saved me from getting hit.
Yeah, these spider enemies are not that scary now.
Nice.
Okay, we got one heart here.
Potential self-damage coming up.
But that would mean sacrificing the blue.
Actually, right now we need demon chance.
Hold up, we gotta change the strategies here.
We gotta keep the buffer for now.
That was close.
Yep, yep.
Oh, man, when they jump at you and you kill them right before they hit you, huh?
Okay, I'm gonna save that key.
Oh,
to the rock!
You know what?
Push it!
It did destroy the tinted rock!
Man.
That's too bad.
Hey, a buffer.
Sick.
So, where do I use my key?
Probably on the treasure room, wherever it is.
Don't do that.
I realized I should have gone for the boss right now, actually, because I have the buffer now, right?
If I lose the buffer here now, that would be terrible, and then, you know...
Not good.
I should have just gone for the boss while I had it.
Or while I still have it.
Oh god, oh god!
See, this is what I'm talking about.
Bob's rotten head.
Is that the one where I just make a bomb?
Oh yeah, it is.
Actually, nice.
Why am I going in here when I just said I shouldn't go in here?
Fuck, I'm on autopilot when I play this game, man.
Well, we got the treasure room, at least.
Buffer gone!
I hate when my own predictions come true regarding that stuff.
It's self-fulfilling.
A sharp straw?
Feels instant damage to all enemies.
Damage is equal to Isaac's tear damage plus 10% of the enemy's max health.
He has to also spawn a half red heart.
I don't like that.
That was bad.
No thanks.
I'm good.
I would like one more coin, though.
Come on, one more.
Give me that.
Buffer acquired.
Man, we're at 14 now.
What is that one?
Using an uncharged item will exchange half a red heart.
I could also re-roll, but nah, probably not worth it.
We're going to save the money.
Here we go, with a buffer.
I'm going to throw a bomb at him.
Oh my god.
I really should have waited until he peeped his head up like that.
Why did I try to do it when he was in motion?
That was bad.
Hey, what was that just now?
Something exploded.
Oh, it was his bomb.
Blood clods.
Yeah, why not?
Oh, hey, actually.
Whoa, this could...
This could actually be good, but then again...
The Satanic Bible.
We gotta take that.
No matter what happens, man, we gotta take that.
I was just to give a long-winded explanation of why the left item is the right choice, and then I saw what the right item was, and I was like, scratch that, we're taking that.
This is gonna do it.
The only thing is now, we need to find a way to teleport back from Mom's room, right?
This is the big one.
Need a card for that.
Or something else that allows us to teleport.
Gotta keep an eye out.
Oh, god.
Dude!
Hate when you get stuck on a little ledge like that.
It was terrible.
Oh!
Wow.
Ooh, we're gonna get three out of three!
Gimme that.
Monster the manual.
Gimme that back.
Dude, that's nice.
It's a very good progression here that we have going on.
Holy
dee.
Seraphim.
Sure.
I'm not very excited about this one, but that's okay.
I gotta find batteries.
That's what I need to do.
Shit.
That was a mistake.
Let's kill those guys.
Then we can worry about the other guy after.
Come on, come on!
Thank you.
Blackheart.
Could get in here, but is it worth it?
Not sure.
Damage is good.
I'm gonna go in here because we need as much...
Ah, we don't have a key.
I was about to say we need as much charge as possible.
And by clearing rooms, you get charged, right?
Okay.
I think there's a pretty good chance we can do this.
I just need to find a teleport card.
Oh god, that was a bit too risky.
Oish!
No!
Boss?
Yeah, okay, go.
Gertie.
Oh my god, really.
Gertie is actually kind of difficult.
Guppy's head.
Uh, man, it's an active.
It costs a red heart for that?
That's not even close to being worth it.
I got things to do here.
Sick.
Thank you for the battery.
Ah, I'm actually gonna get in here.
Totally worth.
Come here.
Okay, we got a shop.
15 coins.
Again?
This is what I mean.
Like, did you see how many items were in the menu?
I'm seeing the same fucking items every run.
This item I see every run, this item I see every run.
Or some variation of this item, you know?
Fanny pack, chance to drop a pickup when taking damage, and...
as I can hold two cards at once.
Actually...
we need this.
Two of hearts.
Useless.
We're not gonna get any more red hearts anyway.
Yeah, let's go.
I'm done here.
Samson looks so fancy with that monocle.
I almost ran into that thing.
Imagine.
I think I would have cried in real life.
A lot of demon chance here.
Damage is good.
I would love to get some kind of item that makes my charges go up faster.
This is what's really gonna catapult me, you know?
Whoa.
What's that?
Wheel of Fortune.
I need my teleport.
Ah, man.
Mistake.
I could have avoided that, for sure.
Oh, no.
Nah, man.
I know where it's gonna hit as well, you know?
It's every time I fall for it.
Oh, come on.
Blow him up.
Nice.
Suicide king.
Kills Isaac and spawns 10...
Excuse me?
That's gotta be for Lazarus.
Yeah, I mean...
Hello?
That sounds horrible.
Man, what are these shit items?
Come on.
Ain't nothing good.
I need that as Azel luck.
Heh heh.
Maybe I'll find the TV remote, or whatever, and turn into Azel.
Save the run.
Okay, well, we have a pretty high demon chance, and good damage here, so...
Oh my gosh!
The Pact!
Ooh, two black hearts, damage, tears?
You best believe it.
Dude, I didn't realize.
That it was two blue hearts that it cost.
I thought...
It was free.
I thought it was free.
I could've died!
Jesus Christ!
Wow.
Well...
That's scary.
Let's get that little last battery here.
Oh, okay.
Wow, he died fast.
We're rocking only black hearts now, it seems.
Ready for the next door?
I think we should move on.
I can't believe it.
Like, why is the item that spawned there costing hearts?
Is it because of something I picked up?
That should be like a non...
a hard-cost item.
That was a terrible way to say that, but you know.
Uh...
Activating this before defeating the current floor's boss will replace the boss reward with a devil deal item that costs health to claim.
You see, that's the explanation right there.
It is actually written black on white in that book.
It says it right there.
It makes sense.
That is it.
I see now.
I need to stack a blue heart if you don't mind.
Like, ten?
Would you kindly grant that to me?
The floating heads are more dangerous.
Okay, it's not a teleport, but...
it's something.
But I mean, if I don't get a teleport, then it's just rip.
Right?
There's like nothing else I can do.
I'm basically at the mercy of RNG.
When I play this character.
Jackie!
Oh my god, you almost...
It's fair, though.
She wants food.
She should have had it actually like 30 minutes ago.
I gotta go feed her right after this.
Hold on, let me see.
Jackie, you still have food!
There's literally like...
one third of a portion in your bowl.
I guess she's just picking.
She's like, no, I want the fresh food.
I don't want yesterday's food.
Which is fair, I guess.
But like, sometimes she do be like that, you know?
Like, she'll have half a bowl and she'll come...
What do you want?
Then I put the food down, like fill it up, and she goes crazy on it.
Isn't that weird?
Familiar that bounces around the room and explodes?
Yeah.
So incredibly underwhelming.
This item is actually so bad.
Because you're relying on the DVD icon, you know?
And you can't trust that one.
Like, look at it, it's not doing shit.
It's just avoiding everyone, actually.
There we go, it did something.
Impressive.
Okay.
A sack.
Spawns a sack.
Coins have a 10% chance to be converted to a sack.
Oh, the pickets have a 20...
What is the sack?
I think I had this once before, but...
Oh, oh, oh, that's a sack, of course.
Right.
That's what a sack is.
Makes sense.
The gate.
Oh my god.
Just kill him.
Yeah, good.
Kill him before he spawns anymore.
Ha!
Horror of... wait!
So this one costs three blue.
Hmm...
This is actually good for me.
The problem is, I need a bit more health.
I'm gonna go back and recharge.
Oh!
Almost stepped on that.
Can I do something in here?
Nothing.
I really need that item.
Oh, crap.
Let's check this out.
Wow.
Okay.
They're trying to cut me off!
A card spawn?
Ooh.
That's what I need, baby.
So glad I went back.
No!
Fucking gravity!
Hate it!
Oh, well now the dreams are totally dead.
We're not getting that item anymore.
How a sad thing could happen to me like that.
I don't know.
You explode?
We could get lucky here.
Man, I wish I could fly.
I wish I could touch this guy.
Something about far away.
Battery!
Only two...
okay.
That's not a lot.
I think my only option...
is to get that last HP and then...
I have six bombs.
I could look for secrets.
It's not here because there's a flame in the way.
Could be here, actually.
Yeah, so far looking good.
Let me see the... ooh.
Room in here.
Also clear.
Let's try.
No!
Okay.
So it's not there.
It could be up here, maybe.
I mean, it could be anywhere.
Oh, that's a lot of bombs, actually.
That may... yeah, actually, that's worth it.
Thanks!
Is that a hint?
It's not.
Mmm, maybe here?
Dang it!
Everything in this run is relying on me getting that horror babylon.
I... no, I'm not gonna go in there.
Oh, wait, I forgot.
I have two... I can switch cards as well.
That's right.
That's a thing.
Maybe here.
That's sort of centralized.
No, this one for sure, though.
Yeah!
Good.
What is that?
Ooh, plus one health?
So... oh my god!
There it is!
That's what I'd be needing!
Thanks, fellas!
I'll go grab that item immediately.
We're gonna become a whore.
Wait, where was that?
Was it?
Oh, wait a minute.
Oh, it's still here, thank god.
Wait, it only costs one red heart now!
Because I got a red heart, I guess.
That's nice!
Yeah!
My final form!
Very nice.
Okay.
I forgot to check how much damage I had before this, but it was definitely not six.
We still gotta play super safe.
Like, we don't have a lot of HP.
We have to prepare.
Ho, ho, ho!
That was a bit risky.
Battery!
Wait, what was that?
The world?
The world.
Nice!
Uh, let me see the map.
Ah, ha!
Well, in that case, we're going the other way.
Ansys!
Ah, but we don't need that right now.
Next time, but I'm gonna keep my... the moon, of course.
We can have both, right?
Oh my god.
This way.
Motherfucker.
Oh, man, that was close!
Leave!
Get me out of here!
What's that?
Book of Sin.
Why not?
Not that amazing, though.
Let's go this way.
Okay.
Got a secret in here.
Be good to me, be good to me.
No!
I mean, okay, we got money right before the... buying room.
The Joker!
Well...
Don't mind if I do!
But the black powder, I hate that.
What a shitty room.
I'm out.
Thanks.
Oh, wait, this is the way to the shop.
Hivemind.
Blueflies and spiders do double damage.
Flying spider familiars do increase damage.
Reveal secret rooms on the map.
Well, we have ansys.
We may not need this.
Give me that.
Yeah.
I could take both, actually.
I just realized I was rich.
Yeah, why not?
He wants hearts, I'm not giving it to him.
Another secret here?
Okay, wait, so that one is actually kind of way off in the corner.
I guess there is no rhyme or reason to this.
The moon, the magician...
So wait, I guess I don't need answers anymore.
That one is useless to me.
Let's do that one.
This wall.
What's in here?
Battery is huge!
Secret room, stars...
I kind of like this.
I'm taking that.
We have the moon.
Yeah, the moon and the stars.
Isn't that fitting?
I like that.
Mom!
What do you want from me?
Mom is angry.
Yeah, the bomb worked!
Finally, I hit her with it.
I mean, keep doing that and I'm happy.
Shit.
Devil...
Hold on.
So wait, why is this one only 1.05 now?
Last time it was like 2 point something.
Gimme that.
Let's see here.
Oh right, we know what this is.
It's a shitty item.
Okay, so here we go.
Let's do...
The stars.
Right?
Okay.
Now where did I start?
I think down here-ish.
Actually, I can take this too.
Is this where I started?
It is!
We lost damage from that.
Oh, wait a sec!
It got consumed!
I see how that works!
And you know what, I think I understand the lore behind this now.
So, Polaroid or negative, it's essentially the same image, right?
One is just before going into the dark room, I guess, and getting processed.
So, looking at that image reminds you of the past, you know?
With Dad and Mom, and that's why we're going into this place.
That's why we're seeing and hearing what we're hearing and seeing.
You know?
It kind of makes sense.
I mean, in hindsight, that's obvious, but I wasn't thinking about it the first time I went in here.
Gehenna?
Excuse me?
That's some demon shit!
Uh...
Wait a minute, this is interesting.
So, I gotta...
step on that.
Ha!
What was the point of that?
Oh, I got a key.
Nice.
Well, secret room has been revealed.
This is probably going to be super difficult.
I don't know what the fuck this place is, and...
I'm scared, you know?
He's about to charge.
Oh my god, he lasered me.
Show me the goods.
Three cards!
Oh god, don't you dare take my battery.
Justice!
Aww...
Too bad.
Troll bombs, I'll take this.
Another secret room down here.
Oh wait, we gotta kill this portal, otherwise it's going to keep spawning things.
Oh god!
Fuck me!
Okay, nice.
This guy's going to go buck wild now.
Use the Bible.
Nice, more battery.
So, it should be...
Wait, how do I get in there?
What?
I think I may have to loop into it somehow?
From the left?
That's weird.
Oh my god!
So I can't kill that guy, you gotta kill the small guys first.
We go this way now.
Whoa!
What are these enemies?
How is this game still giving me new areas?
It's breaking my mind a little bit.
Huge with the batteries though.
Boss, I'm not going to take these two yet, because I just need to clear one more room to get...
Oh wait, how am I going to... I'm not the answer.
These guys are not too bad.
Little demon ghosts.
I like those.
What was that one?
It places all chests to spawn with red chests.
I mean, okay.
Is this it?
Oh wait, it's over here, I'm dumb.
Holy shit!
I like that more.
Reveals the map, may as well do it.
What's this?
Judgement.
Another one of those.
Nope, nope, nope, nope, nope, nope.
Joker.
Hey, devil or angel?
There's also a treasure room.
Let me take this one.
Show me the goods.
There's my sulfur.
And mark.
Oh, well, well, well.
Wait, this is going to take me to three out of three on Leviathan.
I don't know what that means, but I kind of want to do it.
Then again, I kind of want to keep my Bible as well.
Give me that for sure.
If I take this, I'm going to be at three black hearts, man.
I think I need to keep my Bible.
I need to keep up the...
But then again, if I'm about to fight a boss, I'm not going to be able to refresh very much.
Ooh, that's a tough one.
Then again, it's only going to give me Brimstone, right?
Like, my damage is kind of good right now.
I'm going to play it safe, fuck it.
I'm too scared, okay?
Also, I want to go to the treasure room first, just to see what we get.
Who knows what could happen.
And look at this, we got to do this here.
Get another black heart, of course.
Whoa.
Cricket's body.
Tears, less range.
Tears blend into four half-damaged tears on the hit.
That sounds pretty cool, actually.
But what about this?
I'm taking that.
That's going to provide some good AOE, I guess.
Less range, though?
Ooh, now I kind of want to take the Brimstone.
Imagine Brimstone with this.
Splitting that into multiple Brimstones?
Sounds crazy, doesn't it?
Yeah, we got to do that.
Let me see what we got in here first.
Cart, a ladder, oh, this is kind of boring.
May as well buy the carts.
Justice, what was that?
Oh, okay.
This one is unknown.
Ah, that was the sun.
But wait, the sun also does something else, it reveals the map and shit.
But we already have it revealed, so whatever.
Bombs.
That's huge!
Yo!
Brimstone, I'm coming for you.
I'm coming.
But first, we clear a little bit more to get a couple more juices squeezed out of this satanic Bible box, you know?
Oh my goodness, oh my goodness!
No!
These guys just won't die.
Dude, the Splitting Tears is helping so much here.
Guppy's tail... increases, yeah, whatever.
Not that I care too much about that.
I can get it.
Yoink!
And this guy...
He's gonna give me something good, trust.
Come on.
Oh, battery, that's right!
Give me battery, baby!
Dude, if I can find a way to get money...
I'm golden.
Okay, alright, alright.
Here's this again.
Oh my goodness.
Wow!
No!
Damn!
Okay, well, I think that's it.
I got no more coins, I'm gonna blow you up, sorry.
Cute pen, slowing... yeah, actually!
I need all the help I can get, combat-wise, right now.
Let's sit back down and explore the rest.
Fuck, I should've...
Dude, I shouldn't have blown him up, I should've come back.
I maybe could've given him more money, right?
Whoops.
Blunder.
Wait, where am I going?
I'm going... down.
But how do I get down?
This way, I guess.
Yeah.
And then this way...
Whoa!
Okay, we pretty much cleared it now.
So, I'm gonna go back and change.
Yeah.
No, uh, yes, boss, boss, boss.
Wait, no, here, here.
Ah, but wait a minute!
We can't even go back inside.
Frick.
I cannot believe it.
Uh, you know what, give me this one.
The moon.
I wanna see if there's a secret room in the home.
Oh, right, this...
Maybe he gambled.
Right?
That is the usual answer.
At least we're gonna get more black hearts, I guess.
The thing is, though, do I wanna ascend yet?
I think so, yeah.
Maybe that's why Isaac is so obsessed with gambling, you know?
He got it from his father.
Ah, fuck off.
Ooh, nice.
Jesus.
I just realized we gotta take care of this red heart.
We gotta get rid of it.
Otherwise, I'm not doing any damage.
Uh...
Whoa.
I was hoping I could find something here.
Shit.
Wait, what?
Didn't I just clear this room?
I'm losing my damn mind.
No.
Okay, fine, take me.
I need to find, like... This is bad.
I need, uh...
Guys, this is bad.
This red heart needs to go.
That's all my damage.
Yeah.
I come back for you.
Uh, maybe at this point, it may be worth it.
There's also another one I left behind.
I forgot which one that was.
Um...
I think it came a little earlier in the run.
There was something else I found.
But I also disregarded it at the time.
I mean, obviously, we gotta try and get full HP before we do.
No, what?
How?
Why did I get hit by it?
I don't believe that.
Take my money.
Uh, yeah.
Oh, I got the devil, I see.
I was like, where's my pill?
But everything got converted to pills, right?
That's the one.
Uh,
maybe I'll take it.
No, not yet, not yet.
Uh,
don't take it yet.
We're not gonna take it yet.
Oh no, this thing is crazy.
Dude, this room is gonna be insane.
Or not.
He had way more HP last time.
Now I take this.
Oh, man.
Uh, okay, but wait, wait, wait.
Before I go up, I may form a bit more HP.
Don't go up yet.
Getting battery.
Getting Grey Goose.
And Burberry Socks.
Fuck me.
This may be in the realm of, maybe it's not worth it anymore.
To clear.
Let's go up.
Okay.
I need to get rid of this one.
Red Heart, man.
This is actually ruining the whole run right now.
And I don't think I can, because there's not gonna be a blood donation machine here, I don't think.
Hey, look at that!
Haha, almost took it!
It's actually bad if I take that.
Careful, careful.
That's good, I'll take that.
No!
Hey, another Blue Heart!
Come on.
Okay, I can go up here.
Whoa!
Empress gained... oh, that's actually big for me.
I think I need to exchange my...
Like, I have buff cards right now, this is what's gonna help me.
I'm gonna walk around, I need to see if I can find a way to reduce my Red Hearts.
Focus.
That's mine, that's not an enemy.
Jesus Christ!
Hey, sick!
We're actually almost full health.
Um...
I'm trying to think, if I'm at this HP anyway, and I'm not gonna be able to reduce it...
Maybe I'll just take the other Red Hearts.
Oh, that's the one, that's the one!
I don't want that still, that's so bad.
Yeah, fuck that.
Nah, I'm not gonna... maybe there's a way.
Maybe there's a way.
Take me.
I need to hear this.
Dude, that voice was crazy at the end there when he said, I'm sorry, Isaac.
At least it seems like he's aware that he was maybe causing problems and he decided to leave, like...
Dude, that is a good guy.
No, maybe he was gambling sure and he was being, you know, a little careless with that.
But he didn't realize what effect that would have, you know?
What's that?
Aewoss?
Aewoss!
Yo!
Let's try and get further down!
That sounds exciting as hell.
That's a floor decoration.
Oh no, it's... what is this?
Oh!
No way!
Wait, what?
All bomb pickup, double... that's not...
Oh, that's my way to reduce my hearts!
Yes!
I was like, I don't want that.
Oh, that's it, baby!
It didn't give me that much damage, I will say, though.
That was not that great.
It's like 1.6 or so.
I can ascend here?
Wait...
Hold on a minute.
Not yet.
I need my other card.
I need this card.
We have Empress and Strength, we're gonna... let me just remind myself.
Strength is that, and...
How do I see my...
Oh, there we go.
Yeah, I hope that stacks when I apply both.
We'll see.
Here we go!
We're home!
Matchbook, a black heart, three bombs.
Yeah, actually.
I don't think I want the trinket, though.
Okay, so let me check.
Oh, we can probably go find that key again.
Has anything changed?
Wait, why is there like a shadow here?
You see that?
That's weird.
Maybe like a rendering error.
I don't know.
Okay.
TV has been activated.
Mom's pearls.
Range plus lock up.
Two out of three on Mom, man.
I want one more on Mom.
I'm not sure what it does, though, but I want it.
So, wait a minute, how do we do this last time?
I need to blow something up.
Was it just this chest?
It may have been.
Can I not... Oh, man, I can't do the same thing, though.
Okay, here we go.
Dude, let's do this.
I got full HP!
Here we... Oh, that's so creepy.
Dogman.
It's like an unborn child.
Cards have been activated.
16.9 damage, baby!
16.9 gigawatts!
Oh, the TV, right.
Dude, calm down, calm down, calm down.
Okay, okay, good, good.
Now we gotta focus.
What's happening?
Okay, you're doing that.
Just keep dodging.
Dodge that shit.
Whoa!
Okay, okay.
Dude, we're doing good damage here.
Whoa, yes!
Oh, man.
Oh, my God, we're turning into an angel.
That's hell.
Whoa, is that ultra mega Giga Satan?
What is that?
Huh?
We're side-scrolling, huh?
Okay.
Sure.
That's cool.
Oh, my God.
I can't hit anything.
There's flies everywhere.
Dude, I thought we were done.
No, we're gonna lose here, probably.
Oh, my God.
What the...
Oh, thank God.
Oh, wait, is there four of them?
Look at the background.
Oh, shit.
Oh, bombs are just gonna fall down because gravity exists.
Whatever you say.
I'm so dead, I'm so dead.
There is no chance.
I don't even know what I'm getting hit by.
I am so dead.
Yeah.
Oh, wait, nice.
He's probably gonna charge across the screen, I imagine.
No, okay, okay.
Oh, you bastard.
Oh, he mad now.
He angry as hell.
What are you doing?
Okay.
Calm down now.
Calm down.
Oh, man.
Here he comes.
What are you doing?
I can't experiment because I have no HP.
Yeah, it's over.
Oh, fuck.
All right, well, that's gotta end it.
That's too much Isaac in one session anyway.
That was a good attempt.
Got far on that one.
Very cool.
Well, next time I have something to look forward to because I need to punish this guy, guys.
This is getting personal now.
Like, it just keeps going and going and going.
Rough.
Uh-oh, wait, shut your face.
Oh, wait, okay, okay.
Do we have trouble with spoilers?
Feel free to delete all spoilers if people are spoiling something that I missed.
Don't let me know.
I will figure it out on my own, guys.
Whatever it is, okay?
Don't worry.
I'll tell you this, if you tell me what it is, then it's gonna be not good for me.
You know?
Oh, wait, it's emote only.
Well, you can't spoil me now, can you?
So let me ask you yes and no questions, then.
Let's see if you all converge on the same smiley here.
Was that an awesome stream or what?
Except the first half.
The first half sucks, didn't it?
You can answer.
I love that.
We should do this more.
Emote only chat.
Dude, I cannot believe.
Dude, I've been streaming for five and a half hours!
I gotta go feed Jackie, even though she still has food.
She wants the fresh food.
Thank you so much for watching.
I'm actually just gonna go immediately.
Even though there's like 500 people watching, what's up, guys?
It's awesome that you're here.
This was a blast of a stream.
Thank you for being here.
I appreciate it.
More Isaac to come.
I will see you in the next stream.
Thank you, everybody.
Thank you.
This was a good one.
Bye-bye.